<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[LUKE'S IELTS ONLINE]]></title>
  <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-12T17:42:37+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[somilk12]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sample essay for my own use ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/09/sample-essay-for-my-own-use/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/09/sample-essay-for-my-own-use</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> <em>A long-distance flight consumes the fuel as much as a car consumes in several years time, and causes the same amount of pollution as cars. So some people think we should abandon the non-essential fights (such as for tourism), and it is more efficient than restricting the car use. Give your opinion about it.</em></p>

<p>Tourism has fueled up air travel industry and its thriving creates millions of jobs and billions of revenue each year. Therefore, sorting tourism flights as non-essential is unreasonable and to ban these flights, although it would defuse the conflict between energy crisis and commercial profits temporarily, is to backfire both airtravel and tourism industry.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It is, indeed, reported that a long-distance flight consumes the amount of fuel that a car consumes in seven years. But it is also reported that major aerodynamic companies are investing both huge money and labor in the invention and improvement of energy-efficient engine and light materials to cut off fuel consumption and pollution. They are motivated to do so because fuel consumption accounts for up to 70% in their total running cost and the results are promising, light materials, more dual batteries and new engine have been invented and put into use, and they made a less 20%-40% fuel consumption possible.</p>

<p>In terms of air pollution, banning flights is not an effective way either. Traveling by flight has become an essential part for most modern people, including not only foreign trade businessmen, international journalists but also ordinary people who would travel or study abroad. the manmade prohibition will inconvenience these activities drastically and thus trigger public anger or even protests. It is democratic society, any decision made against the public’s interests would definitely araise mass dissensus, which would be a huge hurdle to the implementation.</p>

<p>Prohibiting is not the answer to everything that causes problems temporarily. To make a sensible policy is firstly to investigate the causes of the problems and then come up solutions accordingly. Any surfaced or immediate policy could, at best, scratch the surface of the problem and more often, creates more troubles than it solves. The banning of flight according to the so-called necessity would cause the latter, because it jump to the conclusion based on a single fact-huge consumption and pollution, but neglect the necessity of flights to the public and the inconvenience and anger that would come after such rude and much-too-simple solution. While others alternatives bring in good news, people, especially those policy makers, should at least give them a try. The banning, if needed, should be the last step to take, because it is just a passive way to solve any problem.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sample essay for my own use ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/sample-essay-for-my-own-use/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/sample-essay-for-my-own-use</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Some people think that traditional culture is being damaged as it is used as a tool to make money in the tourism industry. Others think it is the only way to preserve and protect culture and tradition. Discuss both views and give your own opinion.</strong></p>

<p>Official reports give information on the huge amount of revenue that tourism generated every year. However, the worry about the damage brought by this prospering industry is also mounting, the damage to local culture and tradition in particular. Whether tourism is the culprit behind the culture damage or the only protector for local culture and tradition has remained unsettled and it is time we have a close look on both arguments.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Tourism is a way but not the only way to protect culture and tradition. Today,  tourism industry ranks the fourth in the GDP contributing sector globally and it has created millions of jobs and more importantly brought in billions of revenue each year. This amount of money, as believed, can be used in the protection and maintainance of local historic relics and traditional culture because these cultural heritage is the biggest selling point in local tourism development. So it is the virtuous circle which generated money from and for local culture and tradition and a good way to protect and preserve indigenous culture.</p>

<p>On the other hand, it has been pointed out that tourism industry thrives at the price of local culture and environment. Being made as tourists attractions, local culture and tradition are becoming increasingly ‘artificial’ due to the overwhelming man inference in the process of creating a ‘tourist hot spot’ to attract visitors and money. A number of examples show that in order to attract tourists, many’hilarious and appealing to tourists’ traditional cultures have been rehearsed and put on shows in tourist destinations while other more reserved and difficult-in -understanding traditions are filtered and ignored. This manmade arrangement can be extremely hazardous to the protection of local tradition and culture because it changes the nature of them and more worse, it could make the local people regard the treat their convention and culture in a ‘money-oriented’ way.</p>

<p>Tourism, therefore, is a industry that brings in both good and harm. It is clear that this industry is not the only way to protect and preserve local culture and tradition despite the huge amount of revenue. It is a way to generate money to protect local cultural heritage and this is a worth-mentioned contribution. However, what it does to influence the way local people treat their culture should be supervised carefully, because if not, local culture and tradition would become a tool to earn money for the people instead of being an indispensable part in their lives as they used to be. So the two arguments are both melodramatic and a moderate and carefully-planned  development in tourism industry is now what people call for.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sustainability… A Growing Trend in Today’s Marketplace ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Sustainability-A-Growing-Trend-in-Todays-Marketplace/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Sustainability-A-Growing-Trend-in-Todays-Marketplace</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the continued demand for more energy efficient and environmentally friendly solutions, sustainability has become an important trend when choosing products for retail, healthcare, and other commercial applications.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>With the development of LED technology, advertising display productsare better able to meet these demands more than ever. When compared with other traditional light sources such as fluorescent and incandescent, LED consumes about 40% less power, making it extremely energy efficient.</p>

<p>In addition, it lasts anywhere from 50,000 to 100,000 hours – eliminating the need to replace lamps that can be harmful to the environment because of their mercury content. And, LED’s contain no mercury, making them an environmentally friendly choice.</p>

<p>All of these characteristics make LED technology a popular solution for sustainable projects. The really great thing about LED’s is that there is no sacrificing light quality for sustainability. This technology creates bright, white, uniform illumination making it the ideal choice to promote your product or service through eye-catching graphics. You can choose from a variety of sizes, shapes and profiles based on your specific needs.</p>

<p>Next time, use an LED light box to promote your business, and you’ll help improve your bottom line while also helping the planet!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pornography is everywhere and I think it;s changing how we feel about sex ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Pornography-is-everywhere-and-I-think-its-changing-how-we-feel-about-sex/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Pornography-is-everywhere-and-I-think-its-changing-how-we-feel-about-sex</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We arebattling a tsunami of smut that, far from being postmodern, clever or even sexy, is conceived to appeal to our basest instincts, stereotyping men as brainless Neanderthals and women as legitimate prey.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Thedilemma Why is it only children who we think might want to be protected from pornography? Do the rest of us have to live in this grossly objectifying and demeaning culture just because some people want access to porn? I find it interesting that objection tosexually explicit material finds a place as a parental issue – but it&rsquo;s much wider than that. I predict that there will be movements not only against pornography but actually against sex – that&rsquo;s the logical conclusion of all this, particularly with an ageing demographic. And I feel drawn that way. How important is sex? To whom? Why is it shaping our public and virtual spaces to such a degree?</p>

<p>Mariella replies It&rsquo;s a question I&rsquo;ve been asking myself, too. Just the other night as I drove into London I was confronted by a giant billboard selling me &ldquo;Pussy&rdquo;. There wasn&rsquo;t a feline in sight, just a photo of a new energy drink with the tagline: &ldquo;The drink&rsquo;s pure. It&rsquo;s your mind that&rsquo;s the problem.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I have to admit I&rsquo;m fast losing my sense of humour. It was unacceptable for the BBC to play the No 2 single &ldquo;Ding Dong the Witch is Dead&rdquo; in its entirety during the chart countdown despite it being a legitimate, if childish, way for those who didn&rsquo;t venerate Lady Thatcher to have their voices heard, yet it&rsquo;s OK to advertise a soft drink by naming it after slang for female genitalia? Where was the Advertising Standards Authority when that one was signed off?</p>

<p>We seem to have becomeimmune to the corrosive practice of using women&rsquo;s bodies to sell products and the widespread impact of the avalanche of pornography, spreading like a virus online. The links between demeaning representations of women and girls and the continuing (and in many areas escalating) violence against them is well documented, yet we continue totolerate the abuse of one sex for the supposed delectation of another. It&rsquo;s insulting to the intelligence of grown-ups and incredibly damaging to children. While schools are allowedto opt out of sex education, children increasingly get theirs online by watching the abuse (erroneously labelled pornography) which has replaced the misty-lensed erotica of days gone by.</p>

<p>Recently a friend told me that her 10-year-old son had been sent home from school for grabbing an older girl&rsquo;s breasts in the playground, squeezing them and going &ldquo;barp, barp&rdquo; to impress his little boy gang. When his mortified mother asked what had possessed him, he said he&rsquo;d watched a TV comedy where he&rsquo;d seen a guy do it and everyone laughed. And that&rsquo;s an innocent example. On my recent Radio 4 series Bringing Up Britain, Sue Berelowitz, the deputy children&rsquo;s commissioner, revealed that an entire class of Year 6 kids – 11-year-olds – who they&rsquo;d consulted for their report on the sexualisation of children had all watched pornography online.</p>

<p>Enjoying pornography may be a human right for consenting adults but perhaps we could adopt theGerman model, where those wanting to watch sex online have toopt in by signing up at their local post office. It would certainly sort the men from the boys, quite literally, which would be a step in the right direction. We are battling a tsunami of smut that, far from being postmodern, clever or even sexy, is conceived to appeal to our basest instincts, stereotyping men as brainless Neanderthals and women as legitimate prey. Men should be up in arms about the insult to their intelligence and to the women they love – mothers, sisters, wives and daughters – but the voice of opposition continues to be the preserve of the likes of Women&rsquo;s Hour and a few female commentators branded po-faced hysterics.</p>

<p>Ironically, with sex all around, it&rsquo;s interesting to learn from my postbag that many people feel like you: less and less inclined to actually have it. First our friendships were claimed by the virtual world; now our sex lives seem headed in the same direction. Were I to write a sci-fi novel I&rsquo;d set it in the near future, with humans becoming like the hideous breeder rats in James Herbert&rsquo;s novel Lair – deformed, amorphous lumps doing only what they are programmed for.</p>

<p>Once upon a time I thought the feminists of the 1970s were a pretty humourless lot, but increasingly I&rsquo;m missing their strident voices as we continue to tolerate thestatus quo – the sexual objectification of half of the population while brainwashing the other half to be so primitively programmed they fail to understand the boundaries of mutual respect. Surely it makes losers of both sexes?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Illegal logging robbing people in Africa of livelihoods – Global Witness ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Illegal-logging-robbing-people-in-Africa-of-livelihoods-%E2%80%93-Global-Witness/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Illegal-logging-robbing-people-in-Africa-of-livelihoods-–-Global-Witness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Collusion between political elites, civil servants and logging companies issystematically robbing people of their livelihoods, says a report (pdf) into corrupt forestry practices in Africa.</p>

<p>The extensive granting of &ldquo;shadow permits&rdquo; for small-scale logging in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC), Liberia, Ghana and Cameroon bypasses new laws and environmental safeguards, and is forcing communities to meet their timber needs illegally, says NGO Global Witness.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The report, Logging in the shadows, identifies a &ldquo;hidden&rdquo; pattern of abuse in which hundreds of permits intended to promote small businesses and meet local needs are being allocated to large, often foreign, logging companies. These &ldquo;shadow permits&rdquo; open the door tolucrative, large-scale logging operations, which bypass the oversight of the authorities, it says.</p>

<p>In the DRC, dozens of artisanal logging permits were issued between 2010 and 2012, mostly to foreign industrial companies,violating DRC&rsquo;s forest laws in at least 10 different ways. In Liberia, companies have abused licences known as &ldquo;private use permits&rdquo; to buy a quarter of the country&rsquo;s totallandmass in only two years. In Ghana, the forestry commissionis said to have granted more than 400 logging permits secretly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;This is a veryworrying trend. Logging companies are systematically <strong>colluding with</strong> corrupt officialsto get around laws designed to stop themdecimating forests and abusing those who live in them. This is massivelyundermining international efforts to regulate thetimber trade,&rdquo; said Alexandra Pardal, Europe campaigner at Global Witness.</p>

<p>The report said: &ldquo;European-led reform efforts have focused on large-scale concessions that produce timber for export, but in each country shadow permits have provided aloophole to bypass tighter regulations. Weaknesses in legal frameworks and corruption at all levels of government have enabled companies to continue to export large amounts of timber to the EU, US and China.&rdquo;</p>

<p>According to Global Witness, €12.4bn (£10.5bn) worth of timber considered to pose a &ldquo;high risk&rdquo; of illegality entered the EU in 2011. On 3 March, a new EU law prohibited the import of illegal timber (pdf), but Global Witness and Greenpeace have uncovered suspicious log shipments at EU ports in the past two months.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Unless European and Africanpolicymakers <strong>take urgent action</strong> , shadow permits could become theTrojan horse by which illegal timber is brought into the EU and passed off as legitimate,&rdquo; said Pardal. &ldquo;Timber importers must do proper checks right the way along their supply chains to make sure they know exactly where their timber came from and whether the permit used to get it was legal.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Development must tackle jobs and migration say European thinktanks ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Development-must-tackle-jobs-and-migration-say-European-thinktanks/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Development-must-tackle-jobs-and-migration-say-European-thinktanks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Report says poverty should remain central, but calls for inclusive, sustainable model that emphasises jobs</p>

<p>Rocky road … A woman carrying mangoes walks past men doing laundry in Abidjan. Instability hashampered Ivory Coast&rsquo;s development.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>To eradicate poverty, the international community should pursue a wider and more far-reaching approach to development than was captured in the millennium development goals (MDGs), European thinktanks said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Although poverty should remain a core focus of the new agenda, the objective should be to tackle its causes by adoptinga more inclusive and sustainable development model that emphasises jobs and addresses inequality, according to the Overseas Development Institute (ODI), the European Centre for Development Policy Management and the German Development Institute.</p>

<p>Looking at thediffering experiences of Nepal, Rwanda, Ivory Coast and Peru, the European report on development stressed the importance of &ldquo;national ownership&rdquo;. The four were found to confirm the central importance of domestic political and economic policies as well as the external environment in creating opportunities or difficulties.</p>

<p>The report called on richer countries to collaborate in areas important to development such as international financial regulation, trade, migration and climate change. In a message to the EU in particular, the report called on member states to live up to the principle of policy coherence on development (PCD).</p>

<p>&ldquo;The concept of PCD is central, since it implies that all policies, and not merely development co-operation, should beconducive to development, eg policies in the areas of trade and investment or agriculture and fisheries should promote (or at the very least notthwart) development,&rdquo; said the report.</p>

<p>Claire Melamed from the ODI said some sort of global deal on trade and migration could be part of the agenda for what follows the MDGs when they expire in 2015.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Migration keeps coming up again and again among developing countries although it&rsquo;s one of thehardest political issues in the UK,&rdquo; she said at the OECD global forum on development in Paris last week. &ldquo;For developing countries it&rsquo;s a top priority and they want it to be tackled as part of a 2015 deal, so there has to be some nod to a conversation on migration … it is one of the biggest contributor to benefits to individuals and to countries.&rdquo;</p>

<p>PCD is highlycontentious, as developing countries have objected to what they see as unfair trade treaties being foisted upon them, agricultural subsidies in the US and the EU that underminefood security, and the unwillingness of rich countries to meet their aid commitments.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Official development assistance [ODA] targets will not be reached and PCD remains very difficult in practice,&rdquo; said the report. &ldquo;<strong>But perhaps the most crucial issue has been the failure of the international community to reach agreement on key issues such as climate change and trade or to achieve a stable and transparent international financial system.&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p>The OECD last week reported a drop in ODA for the second year running as countries cut foreign aid at a time of austerity. Aid fell by 4% in real terms last year to $125.7bn (£83bn), following a 2% dip in 2011.</p>

<p> <em>International co-operation, or global partnership</em>  for development, came under MDG eight, and was widely acknowledged as one of the least successful targets at last month&rsquo;s meeting in Bali of the UN high-level panel tasked with developing a post-2015 framework. The report said more extensive and reliable international action and support for development should be a core element of a new framework.</p>

<p> <em>Case studies</em>  <strong>confirmed</strong>  the fundamental importance of links with the global economy, financial flows, trade, migration and international co-operation – including south-south co-operation – in determining national development, said the report. Nepal, which integrated the MDGs into development plans, relied on remittances to support progress towards the targets. Rwanda, where the MDGs have played a central role, relies heavily on ODA, much of it in the form of budget support, which brings its own problems, and has made progress in mobilising domestic resources through taxation.</p>

<p>Ivory Coast has relied heavily on commodity exports, but progress towards the MDGs suffered as a result of instability. In Peru, the MDGs have been of limited relevance because of a pre-existing development consensus.</p>

<p>&ldquo;A new framework should pay more careful attention to how global goals relate to national policy needs and targets, respecting domestic policy space and linking national and international efforts in a mutually supportive and flexible manner,&rdquo; said the report.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saving Lives Livelihoods and Life ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/29/Saving-Lives-Livelihoods-and-Life/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-29T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/29/Saving-Lives-Livelihoods-and-Life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By Harold E. Varmus, Director of the U.S. National Cancer Institute; and Robert D. Hormats, Under Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment</p>

<p>For many people, the term biodiversity might seem highly technical and irrelevant to their day to day concerns. If you think that, think again. It may just save your life.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Biological diversity—or biodiversity—simplyrefers to the variety of plants, animals, and other living things on Earth.  <strong>The Earth’s biodiversity has an immense impact on our daily lives and cannot be taken for granted.</strong>  Today, Earth Day, is a chance to reflect on the value of our planet’s biodiversity and to take action to ensure that it is protected.</p>

<p>Tragically—and to the detriment of all of us— <strong>Earth’s biodiversity is disappearing at an alarming rate.</strong>  <strong>This is due to factors such as  </strong>deforestation, environmental degradation, and habitat destruction from agriculture, settlement, and other uses; pollution; climate change; and chronic over-exploitation or poaching of fish and wildlife species.<strong> </strong> Scientists estimate that the planet is losing species at a rate 1,000 to 10,000 times above the rate of species extinction that would occur normally without human activity. <strong>Particularly disheartening is the fact that</strong>, in many cases, we are losing species before we even know of them or know how they fit into our shared planet.</p>

<p><strong>The benefits of biodiversity are immeasurable</strong>. Biodiversity is the foundation of agriculture, forests, and fisheries.Plants and animals support tourism and trade. Biodiversity in ecosystems plays a critical role in the global carbon cycle and contributes to nutrient and water cycling. The loss of life on Earth—from microscopic bacteria to migratory birds—threatens the proper function of our planet. Moreover, biodiversity loss deprives humanity of scientific insights into the origins and evolution of life,as well as future beneficial discoveries in medicine, agriculture, and other fields.</p>

<p>There are numerous examples of advances stemming from bio-inspiration: The piranha bite-proof scales of the arapaima fish are being studied by scientists and engineers to develop new types of body armor that are strong yet flexible. Lessons learned from biological antifreeze proteins found in the blood of Arctic fish are being used to enhance cyro-preservation techniques for human organ transplants, improve the nutrition and taste of frozen foods, and increase the temperature tolerance of agricultural crops.</p>

<p><strong>Drawing inspiration from nature is not new.</strong> The Wright Brothers’ glider and airplane designs were based, in part, upon their observations of pigeons in flight. Wilbur Wright noticed that pigeons bent the tips of their wings to maintain proper balance and equilibrium in flight. This led to the breakthrough concept of wing-warping, which the Wright Brothers successfully used to control turning in their flier.</p>

<p><strong>Protecting our planet’s biodiversity is especially important to every one of us because it can help make the difference between life and death for ourselves and countless future generations.</strong> Medical history is ripe with examples of chemicals and pharmaceutical products derived from naturally occurring plants or bacteria that prevent or treat serious diseases. Among these are digitalis (found in foxglove and used to treat heart failure for at least three centuries); the many antibiotics found in soil bacteria; artemisinins (first used in China in the third century as an extract of sweet wormwood and now part of the standard treatment for malaria world-wide); taxol (from yew trees) and colchicine (from autumn crocus) used for treatment of many cancers and gout; and even aspirin (from willow bark) used to treat a wide variety of inflammatory disorders, allay pain, and prevent inappropriate clotting and certain cancers.</p>

<p><strong>Biodiversity loss runs the real risk of depriving us of the plants, animals, and microorganisms that could unlock cures for some of mankind’s most devastating ailments.</strong> Therefore—whether we suffer from a headache or heart disease—we all benefit from biodiversity and we all have a strong interest in fighting against the many policies and practices that threaten the variety of life on Earth.</p>

<p><strong>Once a species is gone, it is gone forever. Maintaining the Earth’s biodiversity—the broad and rich variety of life on our planet that is the product of billions of years of evolution—by preserving our forests, jungles, deserts, oceans, estuaries, and other habitats is critical to supporting the development of life-saving medicines and other bio-inspired innovations, as well as to ensuring the continued viability of our planet. Alternatively,</strong> the continued loss of biodiversity will seriously and adversely affect—in countless ways—all species, including Homo sapiens. If that fact fails to encourage all of us to make greater efforts to protect biodiversity, it is hard to know what will.</p>

<p>Harold Varmus, M.D., co-recipient of a Nobel Prize for studies of the genetic basis of cancer, is the Director of the National Cancer Institute. He previously served as President and Chief Executive Officer of Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center and as Director of the National Institutes of Health.</p>

<p>Robert Hormats, Ph.D., is the Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment at the U.S. Department of State. He previously served as Vice Chairman of Goldman Sachs (International), Assistant Secretary of State for Economic and Business Affairs, and Ambassador and Deputy U.S. Trade Representative.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Children and apps Should we fear the iNanny ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/29/Children-and-apps-Should-we-fear-the-iNanny/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-29T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/29/Children-and-apps-Should-we-fear-the-iNanny</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, a four-year-old was treated for screen addiction. Emma Cook investigates the dangerous seduction of smartphones and tablets</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s Saturday morning and my children bunch together on the sofa, limbs entwined but minds very much elsewhere, hurled into their several worlds thanks to a couple of iPads and an iPod touch. Everywhere I look there isevidence of heavy usage and dependency. Discarded screen wipes, ear-phone wires and socket extensions trail across the floor.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>&ldquo;Now – now – I need my next charge,&rdquo; gasps my 10-year-old son, whenever his iPad threatens toflatline andslip below 10%.</p>

<p>My two-year-old, Amelia, deflates when Waybuloo fades to black, a signal for me to scrabble around in the detritus for a lead before there&rsquo;s an iTantrum. Amelia responds soinstinctively to a touch-screen, she strokes every flat surface expectantly, waiting for it to light up and activate.</p>

<p>We watch the Apple logo pulse seductively back to life a few minutes later. &ldquo;Look, iPad waking up again!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Once they&rsquo;re all plugged in, I slope back to the kitchen leaving behind a clashing chorus of soundtracks dredged from all corners of the internet; these days Dani&rsquo;s House and Minecraft fused with a little Harlem Shake. We retreat and tune out, my husband on his iPod while I scroll through my online newspaper.</p>

<p> <em>Welcome to my iFamily</em> , one  <strong>where our leisure time is increasingly shaped by tablets, phones and laptops</strong>  – either Apple or its proliferating rivals – and  <strong>where much of our weekend communication is characterised by the following</strong> : Louis, 10: &ldquo;What&rsquo;s your password for iTunes again?&rdquo;; Evie, nine: &ldquo;Mum, Amelia just deleted the Lovefilm app&rdquo;; Amelia: &ldquo;iPad gone black.&rdquo; Cries. So it goes on.</p>

<p>Our family is not alone. Only this week, it emerged that a four-year-old girl is having compulsive behaviour therapy after becoming increasingly &ldquo;distressed and inconsolable&rdquo; when the iPad was taken away. Her use of the device had escalated over the course of a year and she was using it up to four hours a day.</p>

<p>Sometimes, like her parents I&rsquo;m sure, I can&rsquo;t help pining for the monolithic charms of the television – only one remote to control, one voice, programme or soundtrack. Now whenever I turn my back, another screen pops up, another window and volume button with a squawking, tinny soundtrack. It&rsquo;s as if Apple has been breeding in my living room; its slim screens and sleek lines clogging up our shelves and kitchen surfaces, beyond reproach because they look so good. TVs were certainly as addictive but they were never objects of desire in themselves – a double curse.</p>

<p>When our 10-year-old begged us for an iPad mini for Christmas, we caved in partly because we were seduced too. Parents are as childishly enthralled as their teenage sons and tiny babies, which is why they have infiltrated family life <strong>on such an unprecedented scale</strong>  – over 100m iPads had sold worldwide by last year.</p>

<p>The problem is, it&rsquo;s ashared family dependency and I can only really blame myself. I&rsquo;ve recently bought a new laptop and smartphone and am enthralled with – and hooked on – both. I&rsquo;m as addicted as they are, so do I have any right to complain? As a parent, I should monitor and impose many more rules than I do. Instead, Iresort to exasperated threats, shrieking at them when it gets to homework, bath and guitar practice times. With the communal joys of FaceTime, my lame rants and outbursts are often witnessed in real time with great amusement by a bunch of their friends, and parents too for all I know.</p>

<p>Partly I resist being too stringent because, clearly, I enjoy the window of freedom this shared technology affords. Having a toddler third time round isn&rsquo;t the same deal at all – long car journeys are less fraught. Reading a newspaper feature uninterrupted on a Saturday morning is no longer in the realm of fantasy. I&rsquo;m not complaining – I just don&rsquo;t feel this development has led to my finest parenting moments.</p>

<p>Last Friday, I vacuumed the house while Amelia looked at YouTube. As I sucked up the last bit of fluff from behind the sofa, I noticed she was watching Mickey Mouse in Russian. On the upside, her cultural references are diverse these days; she can sing in Korean, thanks to Gangnam Style.</p>

<p>I can also see how much pleasure she derives from the immediacy of the touch screen; her joy at controlling what she consumes with a fingertip, right there and then. While she happily navigates her way around the iPlayer and sends out the odd accidental tweet via her favourite Japanese game app, her grandma sits next to her on her own iPad watching repeats of Pointless.</p>

<p>I know that banning or denying them would be useless. Instead, I prefer to re-frame my limp submission as pragmatic and innovative. Indeed, according to Rose Luckin, professor of learner-centred design at the University of London, specialising in children and technology, I am embracing the future, engaging as a family rather than  <strong>taking an extreme position that would only drive their usage underground.</strong>  She says, &ldquo;In all the time I&rsquo;ve been studying technology and family, the most overwhelmingly successful approach is when you open it up with your children, find out how it works, understand what&rsquo;s good and bad and all engage with it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>In her research, Luckin has discovered that tablets can encourage the sort of social interaction that aids education and learning. &ldquo;One of the key benefits is that they can become a focus for discussion between parents and children. These devices are easy to share – they are not as isolating as PCs used to be. They are a window to a larger experience that can connect you to different parts of family life – pictures, videos, books, learning.&rdquo; We do seem to use these devices in proximity; my children tend not to take them to their bedrooms, they squeeze up on the sofa sharing games and apps.</p>

<p>I know that where it can all unravel is when you treat a tablet as a childminders. &ldquo;I see you&rsquo;re making good use of the iNanny,&rdquo; noted one mother drily when she came to visit. Luckin says, &ldquo;The device on its own won&rsquo;t offer much that is positive. It has to be part of a united family effort of working out how to embrace it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>If not, theirimpact is inevitably divisive. I&rsquo;m extremely aware that family conflict in our household tends to erupt when I&rsquo;ve allowed the children to languish for too long on screens. I vent my guilt and frustration, usually with impotent threats to throw away their chargers, a negative cycle that plays out too often.</p>

<p>Luckin&rsquo;s right – where iPads work best is when we share activities; digesting and reading information for school projects, drawing and creating stuff together with art and animation apps, watching Miranda on the iPlayer.</p>

<p>Now I&rsquo;m more aware of these dynamics, the culture of the iPad has forced us to modify our behaviour … slightly. We do manage to ringfence time, scheduling hours for reading books as well as upping the amount of activities outside the home, one sure way to avoid the temptation altogether.</p>

<p>Often one form of consumption can inform another; Louis admitted recently that he&rsquo;d been watching something very funny on the iPad about the Pink Pussy nightclub. Horrified, I demanded to know what it was and he navigated me swiftly to the new series of Blandings on iPlayer. He enjoys it so much that I now read him PG Wodehouse each evening.</p>

<p>Tablets are intrinsically democratic; they defy the traditional patriarchal model of parenting, which can&rsquo;t be a bad thing. As Luckin says, &ldquo;They&rsquo;ll be confronted with them at school and friends&#8217; houses, so parents need to ask, &lsquo;How do we turn it to our best advantage?&rsquo;&rdquo; In my household, letting Amelia surf YouTube while I pour another glass of wine is probably the truthful answer.</p>

<p><strong>Setting online boundaries for children</strong></p>

<p>• It&rsquo;s not about your child&rsquo;s behaviour but your own. Do you spend your life attached to your smartphone or tablet, never quite switching off, always poised to pounce when the new message alert sounds? If so, take heed: as with the rest of parenting, your child learns much more from what you do than from what you say. If you want to encourage a toddler to concentrate on one thing at a time, don&rsquo;t read bedtime stories with one eye on the Blackberry.</p>

<p>• It&rsquo;s never too early to set boundaries on, for example, the time a child may spend on a tablet. There is not enough research to know what the limits should be – so trust your instincts. Establish in your child&rsquo;s mind that there are rules and limits: these will be different at three than 13, but the first thing to emphasise is the framework.</p>

<p>• If you feel your child is obsessed with a piece of technology or software,reduce its availability. If you feel your child&rsquo;s behaviour is affected adversely, ban its use altogether. You&rsquo;re in charge.</p>

<p>•Abstinence is not the answer. By puberty your child will engage with technology, whatever you allowed when they were tiny. And without a build-up of sensible rules and attitude in early childhood, an older child will find it harder to negotiate the world of smartphones and iPads.</p>

<p>• Your attitude to your child&rsquo;s relationship to technology  <strong>should mirror</strong>  the relationship to food. Left to their own devices, many children would eat chocolate and ice-cream all day long, but no sensible parent would allow that. A child needs a balanced diet of fun and interaction offline, as well as online.</p>

<p>• Learning tosocialise and interact online starts with learning those skills offline, not the other way round.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pensioners hit by spiralling credit card debts forced to take out loans as energy prices soar ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/24/Pensioners-hit-by-spiralling-credit-card-debts-forced-to-take-out-loans-as-energy-prices-soar/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/24/Pensioners-hit-by-spiralling-credit-card-debts-forced-to-take-out-loans-as-energy-prices-soar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Pensioners hit by spiralling credit card debts forced to take out loans as energy prices soar</p>

<p>The Observer, Saturday 22 November 2008</p>

<!--more-->


<p>One in four people is approaching retirement with thousands of pounds worth of debt because they cannot meet the rising cost of living. Nearly half of over-55s are concerned about their depleted income, with one in eight now planning to continue working in order tobolster their income, a report claims.</p>

<p>&lsquo;With unemployment figures estimated to reach two million by December, it is possible that pensioners will find it harder than ever to find work,&rsquo; said Nigel Barlow of Just Retirement, the company behind the research. &lsquo;The likelihood is that poverty among pensioners is set to spiral out of control.&rsquo;</p>

<p> __ <br /></p>

<p> <em>Essential costs</em>  such as gas and electricity have surged by more than 40 per cent this year, meaning that disposable income isshrinking fast. Instead, over-55s are increasingly relying on credit cards, loans and overdrafts to pay their bills. The average credit card debt for the age group is now just over £8,000, according to separate figures from Key Retirement Solutions, a rise of £800 from last year.</p>

<p>A spokeswoman for debt charity the Consumer Credit Counselling Service (CCCS) said the research tallied with its own experience. &lsquo;Our clients are getting older and poorer,&rsquo; said Frances Walker. &lsquo;Last year for the first time more than half were over 40 compared with 44 per cent in 2005, while clients over 60 have the highest levels of debt, averaging nearly £30,000.&rsquo;</p>

<p>The rising figures highlight the consequence of a generation that became used to living off debt, credit cards and unsecured loans. Those who took out the first available credit card in 1967 had expected to pay off their debts by their forties and fifties but have instead found themselves hit by a double whammy of both their children and their parents being financially dependent on them for longer.</p>

<p>&lsquo;Add to these factors the rising cost of living and the credit crunch and you have a problem,&rsquo; said Walker. &lsquo;And we know that once you are retired it is very difficult to clear your debts.&rsquo;</p>

<p>Many retirees will struggle to manage on a rapidly shrinking pension that will have to cover rising living costs as well as pay off debts. The charity Age Concern said that even pensioners who retired owing nothing have since turned to credit cards or loans to pay their bills. &lsquo;On the whole older people havehistorically been more reluctant to get into debt. However, our recent research has shown that hikes in household bills have pushed one in 10 of the poorest pensioners into debt,&rsquo; said Gordon Lishman, director-general of Age Concern. &lsquo;There are also high levels of unsecured debt &#8211; such as credit card debt &#8211; among some people approaching retirement.&rsquo;</p>

<p>More than half of older people are nowcutting back on essentials such as heating and food, according to the charity, while more than a third of older people plan to live in one room of their home to save on fuel bills this winter, according to Help The Aged.</p>

<p>Despite increased living costs&#8230; up to £5bn in benefits is going unclaimed by some of the poorest pensioners because they don&rsquo;t know what they are entitled to &#8230; are worried about the complexity of the process or are embarrassed about claiming.</p>

<p>Sheila Hanham, 69, didn&rsquo;t know benefits were available before she spoke to Age Concern. &lsquo;I had been trying tomake do with very little for a long time and I was desperately worried about how I would get by as I got older. I just felt I couldn&rsquo;t survive,&rsquo; she said.</p>

<p>She now claims pension credit and other benefits and used £3,000 in backdated money owed to her to clear the debt on her credit card, which she had been using to pay bills.</p>

<p>Lishman said: &lsquo;In the currenteconomic turmoil it is important that adequate support and advice is given to the minority of older people who are in debt, and those who are at risk. Many older people will also be looking to the government to announce measures in itspre-budget report to help them with their finances.&rsquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nudge not enough to change lifestyles  ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/23/Nudge-not-enough-to-change-lifestyles/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-23T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/23/Nudge-not-enough-to-change-lifestyles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By Nick TriggleHealth correspondent, BBC News</p>

<p>The government is pilot the nudge theory in a number of areas including smoking cessation</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Plans to get people to adopt healthier lifestyles will not work unless the government is more prepared to use legislation, peers believe.</p>

<p>The House of Lords science and technology committee said ministers seemed to be mistaken in their use of what is known as the nudge theory.</p>

<p>Nudging people is about getting them to change their behaviour without necessarily banning activities.</p>

<p>But the group said that did not mean legislation should not be used at all.</p>

<p>Both the prime minister and Health Secretary Andrew Lansley are known to be admirers of the nudge theory.</p>

<p> <em>It formed a key part of the government&rsquo;s public health strategy which was set out at the end of last year.</em></p>

<p>A unit has also been established in the Cabinet Officeto push ahead with policies. Pilots to get people to quit smoking and increase organ donor registration have already been arranged.</p>

<p>&lsquo;Important lever&#8217;But the cross-party group of peers suggested there was confusion within government over what nudging actually involved, as they had been given different definitions by officials.</p>

<p>The peers also said the government&rsquo;s pursuit ofnon-regulatory steps had created an environment whereby nudge was being seen as something that did not require legislation.</p>

<p><strong>What is nudge?</strong></p>

<p>It is an idea based on a book by Richard Thaler and Cass Sunstein which advocates influencing behaviour by altering the context or environment in which people choose.</p>

<p>It differs from traditional approaches to changing lifestyles which tend to be moreovert.</p>

<p> <em>Conventional measures might include steps such as bans, using tax to increase price or promotional campaigns.</em></p>

<p>But nudge tends to be moresubtle, perhaps involving providing information about social norms.</p>

<p>It can also include changing the environment, such asinstalling fewer lifts in a building to encourage people to use the stairs more.</p>

<p>Another approach is altering the &lsquo;default setting&rsquo; so that people get salad with their meal rather than say chips unless they specifically ask for them.</p>

<p><strong>Why a nudge is not enough</strong></p>

<p> <em>But they said this was not always the case</em> , recommending the government took steps to ensure traffic light labelling appears on food.</p>

<p>This contrasts with thegovernment&rsquo;s tactics to date which have been more focused on using voluntary agreements.</p>

<p>For example, earlier this year ministers launched the &ldquo;responsibility deal&rdquo; which saw more than 170 companies put their names to a series of pledges covering physical activity, alcohol, health at work and food.</p>

<p>The committee is also calling for an independent chief social scientist to be appointed to provide government with &ldquo;robust&rdquo; advice.</p>

<p>Committee chairman Baroness Neuberger said:&ldquo;There are all manner of things that the government want us to do &#8211; lose weight, give up smoking, use the car less, give blood &#8211; but how can they get us to do them?</p>

<p>&ldquo;It won&rsquo;t be easy and this inquiry has shown that it certainly won&rsquo;t be achieved through using nudges, or any other sort ofintervention, in isolation.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Professor Lindsey Davies, president of the UK Faculty of Public Health, said it was a &ldquo;welcome and timely report&rdquo;.</p>

<p> <em>&ldquo;The public health profession has long argued that &lsquo;nudging&rsquo; is but one aspect of a wide programme of interventions to help people make changes in their lives which promote good health and wellbeing.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>A Cabinet Office spokesman said the recommendations would be considered.</p>

<p>But he added: &ldquo;We are glad that they recognise that that the application ofbehavioural insights continues to be an important policy lever for government. These often complement other, more traditional policy tools.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solo Cities How “Living Alone” Is Changing Urban Americ ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/14/Solo-Cities-How-Living-Alone-Is-Changing-Urban-Americ/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/14/Solo-Cities-How-Living-Alone-Is-Changing-Urban-Americ</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by Julie D. Stern</p>

<p>June 28, 2012</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Eric Klinenberg, author of Going Solo: The Extraordinary Rise and Surprising Appeal of Living Alone, discusses how anoutmoded image of singletons, such as the ruggedindividualist shown on screen, is being replaced by an image of active, connected singles who contribute tocommunity vitality.</p>

<p>The rise in living alone is “the biggest modern social change that we’ve yet to name or identify,” said Eric Klinenberg, professor of sociology at New York University. He examined the effect this change is having on cities and suburbs in a keynote presentation at a ULI Terwilliger Center for Housing forum on June 21 in Washington, D.C.</p>

<p>Klinenberg, author of Going Solo: The Extraordinary Rise and Surprising Appeal of Living Alone (The Penguin Press, 2012), uses the term “singleton” to differentiate those who live alone from unmarried “singles,” many of whom live in households with family members or others.</p>

<p>He argued that this trend does not mean what many people assume. Ourold perceptions about those who live alone—that they are sick, neurotic, immoral, and/or lonely—are simply wrong, he said. In fact, he noted, people who live alone are more likely than married people totake advantage of <strong>urban amenities</strong> , to go out at night, to attend public events and engage in other activities that “animate the streets.”</p>

<p>They also are more likely to volunteer with <strong>civic organizations</strong>. “These are not selfish, self-involved, narcissistic people who are not participating incollective life. We have to change our image of who singletons are. Clearly they are a force in cities today.”</p>

<p>Klinenberg presented theintriguing statistics that 27.6 percent of all U.S. households consist of people living alone (compared with fewer than 10 percent in 1950), and that this ispredominantly an urban phenomenon (whereas until the 1950s it was a mostly rural one). In Washington, D.C., and Manhattan, for example, nearly half of all households are single-person ones (48 and 46 percent, respectively). “These arestaggering numbers, and theysay a lot about how we live today,” he added.</p>

<p>Who are these singletons, what types of housing choices are they making, and what will these choices mean for thehousing industry? During the course of his research, Klinenberg came toview the phenomenon of living alone as asocial experiment rather than a social problem. “Why do the most privileged people on earth use their resources to separate from one another?” he asked. The answer, he proposed, is a reflection of values that many view as inherently American: freedom, personal control, and self realization—as well as (and not necessarily paradoxically)both solitude and connection with others.</p>

<p>The rising economic status of women, widespread prosperity, and the “rise of the welfare state” also havedriven up rates of living alone. (Many European nations, including Sweden, Norway, Germany, the Netherlands, Great Britain, and France, have even higher percentages of singletons than the United States.) Yet, he noted, a catastrophic economic situation or thedemise of social security and other support systems could dramaticallyshift the trend.</p>

<p>Klinenberg cited four<strong>primary factors</strong> that are playing roles in this trend and that have broad implications for the development industry:</p>

<p> <strong>Women’s Economic Independence</strong></p>

<p>Single women today represent about 20 percent of all home buyers; they are twice as likely to buy a home as single men.</p>

<p> <strong>The Communications Revolution</strong></p>

<p>Being home alone today means something very different than it did in the past. “We are creating new kinds of sociability; social media are connecting people in new ways,” he suggested, arguing that the best evidence to date implies that the heaviest users of social media also are “the heaviest users of face time”; they are more likely to spend time with others.</p>

<p> <strong>The Rise of Cities—and of Neighborhoods within Cities</strong></p>

<p>As many as 70 percent of the households in some urban neighborhoods consist of a single person. Klinenberg argued thatsuch neighborhoods benefit the entire city by offering the cafés, restaurants, bars, active sidewalks, and other amenities that result in “a booming public life.” They are the “places where we all like to go,” he said.</p>

<p><strong>The Longevity Revolution</strong></p>

<p>More people also are aging alone than ever before. This has clear implications for continuum-of-care retirement communities andassisted-living facilities, places where people can have their own “home” and be close tocompanions, service providers, and amenities.</p>

<p>“Living alone is a hugely significant social change that we misunderstand at our peril,” Klinenberg said, noting that the cities and suburbs that recognize and accept this trend will be more successful than those that do not.</p>

<p>What types of housing attracts singletons? Klinenberg described a residential complex in Stockholm, Sweden, (which he called “the world capital of living alone”) for people 45 and older. The complex looks a lot like many high-end, amenity-rich buildings in New York City, featuring relatively small residential units but a multitude of amenities, including a large health club, a coffee bar, party rooms, public lounge spaces and outdoor terraces.  <strong>It fosters community by requiring all residents to commit to helping with preparation of a shared meal several times a week.</strong></p>

<p>Projects like this, he proposed, could prove attractive to Americans who (sometimes to their surprise) find themselves aging alone—but who want to remain connected with others.</p>

<p>How this trend will play out in housing for younger age groups, and in inner-ring suburbs that could become more popular among young singleton professionals depends in part on whether municipalities can resolve zoning issues and overcome opposition from existing residents. Some zoning requirements, along with community opposition, can make it difficult or impossible to build smaller-scale residential units and the commercial amenities that appeal to people who live alone.</p>

<p>“I think that’s a real issue,” said Klinenberg. “There are a lot of ideas about how to build smaller residential units that connect people to a bigger world, and I hope we can have some good conversations about that.”</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sample essay of schooling and parenting(for my own use) ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/sample-essay-of-schooling-and-parenting%28for-my-own-use%29/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/sample-essay-of-schooling-and-parenting(for-my-own-use)</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> <em>c8t1</em></p>

<p>Children are the future. Therefore, early childhood education is the utmost priority on the importance list concerned by parents, schools and states. When it comes to who should be responsible for educating children into useful adults, there is an ongoing debate. Many advocate that comparing with school education, parenting is of more significance in this aspect.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Such beliefs are not groundless. Above all, parents are the first teacher to children. Their ways of thinking and behaviour decide what their children will be like in the future. As is reported, a child&rsquo;s basic skill of communication and language is formed in the first three years in his/ her life, and this indicates that any verbal and physical movement parents made in these three years will help to build a child&rsquo;s personality and a basic concept about people and the outside world. Moreover, the mindset of being grateful and respectful to good deeds and people are taught by parents. When parents take care of their older parents at home, their ways of helping the elderly have a great reflection on children&#8217; mind, which do lead a young to a lifelong way of showing respect to the old and the needed. Also, the ability of love and being loved is imparted by parents in a tender manner. A kid learn this ability by feeling the most earnest love to himself or herself from parents, and they start getting the importance of love and being loved. A person who can behave appropriately, respect and love others is believed to be a valuable member of society.</p>

<p>However, some still argue that rather than parenting, schooling in fact plays a more influential role in children&#8217; development. In their opinion, a child is supposed to obtain theoretical knowledge of a range of subjects and the ability to win the fierce competition among peers by attending normal schooling.Success it might lead children to, there is hardly any evidence linking schooling to the future of being a good community member in a child. No matter how successful a person could be, financially or academically, there is still a high possibility that a well-school-educated person finally turn out to be a selfish adult who has no basic passion towards human being and community. There are too many examples to illustrate  a higher education qualification dose not guarantee a well manner or behavior in that person. In comparison to parenting, which is widely thought as a necessary and sufficient condition in the process of educating children into valuable adults, schooling is believed only a necessary condition at its best.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gender issues key to low birth rate ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/Gender-issues-key-to-low-birth-rate/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/Gender-issues-key-to-low-birth-rate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In January, Japanese Health Minister Hakuo Yanagisawa visited the city of Matsue to talk to party members about the falling birth rate.</p>

<p> <em>Arresting the decline</em>  would be difficult, he said, because &ldquo;the number of birth-giving machines and devices is fixed&rdquo;.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>&ldquo;All we can ask for is for them to do their best per head,&rdquo; he said.</p>

<p>Mr Yanagisawa&rsquo;s comments did not go down well. Womenreacted angrily to his choice of words, while the oppositionaccused him of blaming women for the fertility crisis.</p>

<p>But the episode didhighlight one thing. Government measuresaimed at boosting fertility have so far failed to <strong>deliver the desired rise.</strong></p>

<p>So what exactlyis behind Japan&rsquo;s low birth rate?</p>

<p><strong>&lsquo;Work or kids&rsquo;</strong></p>

<p> <strong>Across the developed world</strong> , as a general trend, women are working more and marrying later.</p>

<p>But compare Japan with Sweden, for example. More Swedish women work and they marry later, yet the country&rsquo;s birth rate is far healthier. So Japan&rsquo;s troubles cannotbe attributed to these two factors alone.</p>

<p>In Japan, peopleflagged up three separate issuesas obstacles to child-rearing &ndash; <strong>money worries, the problems of working and having a family, and a lack of support for mothers.</strong></p>

<p>&ldquo;Everyonehas the impression that raising a child is very expensive,&rdquo; one Tokyo student said. But many young couples do not have much money.</p>

<p>Pay is often linked to age, while adisproportionate number of young people and women are employed<strong>on</strong>poorly-paid temporary contracts. Child allowances are low, while housing and education costs are high.</p>

<p>The financial situation for young couples can be even harder because many women give up work when they have children &#8211; sometimes reluctantly.</p>

<p>Some workplaces are unwilling to keep jobs open for mothers-to-be, who can come under both direct and indirect pressure to leave.</p>

<p>In small and medium-sized firms, says Dr Kuniko Inoguchi, former minister for gender equality and social affairs, around 70% of pregnant women end up quitting.</p>

<p>For those women who do return to work, things can be hard.</p>

<p>Many struggle to find affordable child care facilities that can keep infants all day. Others discover that although they have jobs, <strong>they bear no resemblance to the ones they left and promotionis no longer a possibility.</strong></p>

<p>&ldquo;Many women want to work and have kids,&rdquo; said Mitsuko Kamaya, a housewife.</p>

<p>&ldquo;But <strong>it&rsquo;s still the case that</strong> it is either work or kids. Women feel that they have to throw one dream or the other away,&rdquo; she said.</p>

<p>&ldquo;If there was a system that guaranteed women could get back to work, I think more would feel secure enough to have kids.&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Hard work</strong></p>

<p>Then there are the practicalities of raising children.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Families used to live with all the generations together,&rdquo; said one Tokyo pensioner.</p>

<p>&ldquo;That was good for everybody, as there were more people around to provide support.&rdquo;</p>

<p>In rural areas where this is still common, birth rates are above the national average. But many young couples live in cramped city apartments far from relatives and when babies are born, husbands tend not to compensate for the lack of family assistance.</p>

<p>According to a lifestyle survey in 2001, married men only spent about 30 minutes each day on household tasks or with their children.</p>

<p><strong>This is partly down to traditional attitudes</strong> &#8211; Japanese men tend not to cook, clean or change nappies. <strong>But another problem is a culture of long working hours, followed by compulsory after-work socialising.</strong></p>

<p>&ldquo;My colleague&rsquo;s wife has just had a baby, but he has to work until 11 o&#8217;clock every night,&rdquo; said one Tokyo businessman.</p>

<p>&ldquo;He only ever sees the baby when it&rsquo;s asleep.&rdquo;</p>

<p> <strong>So child-rearing can, in some cases, prove a lonely and exhausting solo experience for mothers, many of whom then decide to stick with just one child.</strong></p>

<p><strong>Social change</strong></p>

<p>Osaka City has the second lowest birth rate in the country, behind the capital, Tokyo. In 2005 it stood at 1.15 births per woman, well below the national average of 1.26.</p>

<p>In recent years, officials there have worked hard to introduce family-friendly policies. There are now more day care places available for children of working mothers and the facilities are staying open longer each day.</p>

<p>Primary schools are running after-school programmes for children whose parents both work, while stay-at-home mothers can now use a pay-per-hour baby-sitting service when they need some time to themselves.</p>

<p>But the birth rate is not rebounding.</p>

<p>&ldquo;We can try topublicise the idea that having a child is a good experience, and work to create an environment in which women feel secure enough to have one,&rdquo; said Yasuko Baba of the city&rsquo;s Children and Youth Bureau.</p>

<p>&ldquo;But we can&rsquo;t say &lsquo;please have a child&rsquo;. Ultimately it is up to them.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Dr Inoguchi says the government needs to spend more on helping young families. But she says there also needs to be social change so that both men and women have a better balance between work and family.</p>

<p>And the population crisis is helping to highlight where the problems lie.</p>

<p>&ldquo;This very dramatic changing demography and the alarming view that we may not be able to sustain the greying of the population is now leading to &#8211; belatedly and reluctantly &#8211; the mainstreaming of gender issues,&rdquo; she said.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FaceBook  Good or Bad for Communication ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/FaceBook-Good-or-Bad-for-Communication/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/FaceBook-Good-or-Bad-for-Communication</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook started out as a way for like minded students to share their life experiences and stay in touch. But are social networking sites enabling interaction or reducing it to a escapist experience,displacing real interaction in favour of an alternative reality?</p>

<p>To try and answer what is anexistential question, at best, it is necessary to look at the positive and negative impacts of FaceBook on it&#8217;suser community, gleaned from various sources interviewed by the BBC in &ldquo;Online networking &lsquo;harms health&rsquo;&rdquo;.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Social networking can enrich social lives for those separated from family and friends by long distances, bringing them together despite the physical separation. This has recentlycome to light in the number of people in the armed forces using YouTube, FaceBook and Twitter to stay in touch.</p>

<p>Online communication can help those with dysfunctional syndromes achieve a level of social interaction previously difficult or impossible. For some people, interaction with crowds <strong>is made easier</strong>  if they do not actually feel thephysical immersion.</p>

<p>Such sites also provide thoseisolated by disability or environment with a rich and fulfilling social life. For anyone who is unable to leave their own house, social networking has provided a great way to get in touch with people who have similar issues, as well as allowing them to stay in touch with existing networks of friends.</p>

<p>Finally, social networking sites can bring people together with varying backgrounds who might otherwise never have met, and then encourage them to extend that experience into real world social functions.</p>

<p><strong>Negative Impact of FaceBook</strong></p>

<p><strong>Electronic interaction</strong> displaces the social interaction, <strong>keeping people apart</strong> – it is so convenient that peoplelack the drive to actually interact face to face. People aresocial animals,  <strong>in the main</strong> , and removing that pillar can actually affect their social development, especially if started at a young age.</p>

<p>It also changes the way people interact, possibly producing changes that will eventually affect theevolution of social interaction. The lack of face to face communication undermines skills such as reading body language and other indirect communication facilities.</p>

<p>Mass electronic communication may lead to alower quality of social interaction due to thesheer number of participants; the background level of gossip is likely to be higher than in face to face interactions. There&rsquo;s also the inference that online information has less value somehow than real world information, although the same could be said of water cooler office gossip.</p>

<p><strong>On Balance : How Should FaceBook Be Used?</strong></p>

<p> <em>As with other enabling technologies</em> , such as email, web search engines, and online publishing outlets like Wikipedia, the <strong>overall message is that</strong>, <strong>in moderation, Facebook and other networking sites are a good thing.</strong></p>

<p>They let people connect, whether they knew each other in the first place or not – staying in touch or making new friends. Yes, there are potential drawbacks in the form of very public cases where such friendships have degenerated into something more sinister, but the positives far outweigh them.</p>

<p> <em>Success stories include various marriages, business deals, partnerships, and other very encouraging<strong>endorsements</strong> of virtual communication as a form of social interaction.</em></p>

<p>However,relying exclusively on electronic communication for social interaction is likely todamage rather than enrich lives. Everyone, at some point, with very few exceptions, needs the face to face contact in order tomaintain their social skills.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sample essay for youth unemployment(for my own use) ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/09/sample-essay-for-youth-unemployment%28for-my-own-use%29/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/09/sample-essay-for-youth-unemployment(for-my-own-use)</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> <em>rubric: what are the causes and solutions of youth unemployment?</em></p>

<p>Youth unemployment is a chronic issue. This social problem is not a single-cause case but a result from many social forces, especially in economy, culture and the disproportion in higher education arrangement of curriculum. This essay will analyze the major causes behind this trend and highlight some responsible solutions.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Many fresh graduates take graduation as the time being unemployed, while the increasing rate of youth unemployment reconfirms this fear. With the recent break out of economic recession, first in the USA, then in Japan and Europe, this trend has been exacerbated. Under such circumstance, many companies started to cut off its man power as well as limit the number of newly recruited employees. This makes it hard for an experienced worker to keep his or her job, let alone new graduates finding a position in such an economic hardship. Also, it is long been discussed that higher education fails to meet the need of providing the society and labor market with students who master no only theoretical knowledge but practical skills. As a result, the average performance of young graduates at work is relatively unsatisfying, which leads to an avoidance of recruiting first-year graduates in many companies. And this is another factor which intensifies the situation of youth unemployment.</p>

<p>According to those causes analyzed above, several measures should be put into effect in the near future. First of all, an economic recovery is the surefire cure for this situation, which asks for the very effort from governments. Governors can draw a strategy after through study of the job market stimulation policy enacted by Roosevelt-introducing big infrastructure programs to underdeveloped area&#8211;to consume a big number of labors. Secondly, the insufficiency of higher education should be filled as soon as possible, including opening courses about the office manner and dress code in certain company culture, to compensate the scarcity of work experience in students. Again, more connections should be bridged between students and companies. Take Holland for example, it mandates students to accomplish the target of taking internship during college period. This method allows students to have a better acquaintance with the way how a company is operated and how to get along with colleagues in office.</p>

<p>In conclusion, youth unemployment is a social issue which is resulted from many social changes. If the solutions identified above are implemented, the situation of this issue will be largely improved.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sample essay for environmental protection(for my own use) ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/08/Sample-essay-for-environmental-protection%28for-my-own-use%29/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/08/Sample-essay-for-environmental-protection(for-my-own-use)</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> <em>Rubric:</em></p>

<p> <em>Some people think that pollution and damage of environment are resulting from a country&rsquo;s developing and becoming richer, and this is hard to be avoided. To what extent do you agree or disagree?</em></p>

<!--more-->


<p>With the economic boom,the pollution and environmental degradation are becoming increasingly serious. Some people argue that this is the inevitable outcome of a country’s economic development. Personally, I am of this opinion.</p>

<p>The industrial development has thus far consumed a variety of non-renewable resources and produced pollution. Due to industrialization, non-renewable resources, including fossil fuel and other raw materials are consumed at an alarming rate. It is universally acknowledged that these resources are limited and once being depleted, they would not be restored within a short time. More worse is that the consumption of natural resources produces pollutions and it is proved that the consumption of fossil fuel is the main reason behind the ever-severe air pollution.</p>

<p>And until now, human race still is far away from the balance between development and ecosystem sustainability. The anti-pollution measures are futile in front of the irreversible eager of developing economy; the government compromises to the commercial benefits brought by highly-polluted industries, including energy industry and chemistry industry; people hold the view that “environmental conservation is second to economic development”. This shows that economic development has driven people ahead, leaving environmental protection behind.</p>

<p>However, it should be noted that some countries have succeeded in both economic and environmental development. For example, Swiss and some north European countries, such as Norway, have set good examples for other nations about how to develop economy and protect the environment at the same time. But compared with the typical modes of development in most countries, these examples are just some exceptions.</p>

<p>In conclusion, I believe that the economic development is thriving at the price of environment and this is an inevitable trend. However, people should never give up the effort of maintaining environment while developing economy for this effort will certainly pay back when the country is financially and technologically capable of tackling environmental problems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[雅思写作高分表达（积极关系） ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/01/24/%E9%9B%85%E6%80%9D%E5%86%99%E4%BD%9C%E9%AB%98%E5%88%86%E8%A1%A8%E8%BE%BE%EF%BC%88%E7%A7%AF%E6%9E%81%E5%85%B3%E7%B3%BB%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/01/24/雅思写作高分表达（积极关系）</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre><code>            &lt;p style="text-align: left"&gt;有话在前：通过练习熟悉使用这些句型，才能保证在规定的时间内完成作文。否则事与愿违：）
</code></pre>

<p><p style="text-align: left">积极关系</p>

<p><!--more-->Be made (readily/ freely/ publicly/ generally) available for/to sb</p>

<p>可以容易/免费/让公众/普遍得到</p>

<p>e.g. Free medical care must be made available for those too poor to do so.</p>

<p>Provide/give sb deep/penetrating/revealing/ fascinating insights into sth</p>

<p>给予某人深刻的/有启发性的/发人心省的/生动的见识</p>

<p>e.g. The old buidling in cities can give people especially teenagers fascinating insights into the change of history.</p>

<p>acquire/advance/broaden/deepen one’s understanding of sth 获得/增进···见识</p>

<p>= gain/get/obtain insights into</p>

<p>Have better acquaintance with 更了解···</p>

<p>e.g. Have better acquaintance with the local needs than those in other countries so that it utilise the social resources more efficiently</p>

<p>= have better knowledge with</p>

<p>e.g. Local people or government have better knowledge with the operation of charity organization in terms of the oversee of donations, thus ascertaining the transparency of fund arrangement and avoiding misappropriation of the public fund.</p>

<p>Become/be proficient/skillful in/at sth/ in doing 精通，熟练</p>

<p>e.g. student should become proficient in using several languages.</p>

<p>Instill sth in/into sb = inculcate sth in/into sb 灌输某人···</p>

<p>e.g. instill an idea/confidence deeply into sb</p>

<p>inculcate a sense of responsibility in sb</p>

<p>= impart sth to sb 传授···给某人</p>

<p>Be capable of sth/doing sth有能力的，足以胜任的</p>

<p>= be competent to do sth</p>

<p>= Be more than capable of ···完成有能力</p>

<p>e.g. Schools should equip students with practicial skills so that they are competent to find a job under current fierce competition.</p>

<p>Be well/fully aware of/that = be conscious of/that 意识到，注意到</p>

<p>e.g. People have been fully aware of the urgency of environmental protection.</p>

<p>Be the major beneficiaries from = largely benefit from··· 成为最主要的受益人</p>

<p>e.g. In respective of individuals, they are the major beneficiaries from doing their tasks at home in this age of the computer technology</p>

<p>Be conducive/ helpful/ beneficial/instrumental to··· 有利于,对···起作用</p>

<p>= be advantageous to</p>

<p>= be of advantge to = to the advantage of</p>

<p>e.g. be instrumental in bring about an end to the conflict.</p>

<p>An environment conducvie to learning</p>

<p>Be given sufficient/greater autonomy in doing··· 给予足够的/更大的自主权</p>

<p>e.g. students should be given sufficient autonomy in deciding the courses they take as the case may be</p>

<p>Be in the best interest of··· 符合···利益</p>

<p>e.g. Even though most citizens are conscious that recycling garbage can fully utilise natural resources in the best interest of the whole society, they are still reluctant to do so</p>

<p>Become an indispensable part of··· 成为···不可分割的一部分</p>

<p>e.g. car have become an indispennsable part of our lives.</p>

<p>Make use of = turn sth to good account = take advantage of sth 善用/利用机会</p>

<p>e.g. People should put the media to good account.</p>

<p>We should make better use of our resources.</p>

<p>Break down/remove/cross/overcome the barriers打破/消除/跨越/克服障碍</p>

<p>e.g. they believe that sport can cross any barriers.</p>

<p>他们相信体育可以跨越任何障碍。</p>

<p>Get rid of··· 摆脱,消除(不好的感觉,情况)</p>

<p>= rid sb/sth/yourself of sb/sth 消除,解除</p>

<p>= extricate sb/sth/yourself from sth (使)摆脱,脱离,解救,挣脱</p>

<p>e.g. he had managed to extricate himself from most of this official duties.</p>

<p>Alleviate the heavy burden of··· 减轻···重负</p>

<p>e.g Staying at home for work and study can alleviate the heavy burden of transport and energy consumption.</p>

<p>Serve a useful function of 起到有用的功能</p>

<p>= Perform the function of 履行···的功能</p>

<p>= Fulfilll a valuable function in 实现一种有价值的功能</p>

<p>= Serve the purpose of 起到···的目的</p>

<p>= Fulfill an educational purpose 实现一种教育目的</p>

<p>e.g. It is sometimes claimed that zoo perform an improtant function in the protection of endangered or rare species</p>

<p>e.g Apart from serving the practical function of giving people a comfortable shelter, a good building should also fulfill an aesthestic purpsoe by inviting the residents to appreciate its beauty both inside and outside.</p>

<p>e.g. Visiting museum is not only an enjoyable experience for young children, but it also fulfills an important edcuational purpose by exposing them to a rich deposit of history, culture and tradition.</p>

<p>Be/get accustomed to doing/sth 习惯于···</p>

<p>= be/get used to doing/sth</p>

<p>e.g. Students should not get accustomed to relying on others’ help.</p>

<p>Adapt yourself to sth/ doing 适应(新环境)</p>

<p>= adjust oneself to sth/ doing</p>

<p>e.g. students should adjust themselves to current fierce competition</p>

<p>Serve/ satisfy/ cater to the needs of··· 满足···要求</p>

<p>e.g. satisfy/cater to the needs of tourists from abroad</p>

<p>serve the needs of future generations</p>

<p>Cater for sth 迎合</p>

<p>e.g. Catering for international tours, the local government commits more money to improve local infrastructure.</p>

<p>Provide a solid foundation for··· 提供巩固的基础</p>

<p>e.g. respect and friendship provide a solid foundation for marriage.</p>

<p>= Lay the foundation on··· 为···提供基础</p>

<p>e.g. Basic science lays the foundation on which any other subjects are built.</p>

<p>Have no more worries about··· 不用再担心</p>

<p>e.g. The owners of companies have no more worries about employees not coming for work, because of the heavy snow storm.</p>

<p>Be immune to 不···(负面的)影响</p>

<p>e.g. The corporate sector has remained largely immune to this crisis.</p>

<p>Immerse oneself in = Commit oneself to sth 潜心于，专心于</p>

<p>e.g. Student should immerse themselves in studying theory in universities instead of learning practical skill</p>

<p>Reach a consensus on 达成共识</p>

<p>e.g. The EC Council of Finance Ministers failed to reach a consensus on the pace of integration</p>

<p>Be brought up to do··· 教养，培养</p>

<p>e.g. It is standard practice that children are brought up to respect the law.</p>

<p>通常来说，小孩子接受教育要遵守法律</p>

<p>Keep the pace with 与···俱进</p>

<p>e.g. A number of advanced professional personnel are needed to keep the pace with the rapid economic development.</p>

<p>With less +名词+动名词组合, greater possibilities of动名词组合 will be taking place someday.</p>

<p>如果少一点的··,··更有可能在某天发生</p>

<p>e.g With less people driving to work or school, greater possibilities of returning us a balance in ecosystem will be taking place someday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[雅思写作高分表达（否定关系） ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/01/24/%E9%9B%85%E6%80%9D%E5%86%99%E4%BD%9C%E9%AB%98%E5%88%86%E8%A1%A8%E8%BE%BE%EF%BC%88%E5%90%A6%E5%AE%9A%E5%85%B3%E7%B3%BB%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/01/24/雅思写作高分表达（否定关系）</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>有话在前：想要熟悉使用这些句型并且在考场派上用场，就得好好练习。不然会导致因为想句型，最后作文没写完。</p>

<p>Serious/distinct/relative lack/ shortage/ absence/ insufficiency/ scarcity of</p>

<!--more-->


<p>= Be lack of/be short of/ be deficient in/ be in need of (严重地/明显地/相对地)缺乏···</p>

<p>Be a hurdle to/ be a hindrance to/ be a barrier to 阻碍···</p>

<p>= confronted with/encounter/erect/put up barriers to</p>

<p>Scratch the surface of the problem 治标不治本</p>

<p>e.g. obviously, this solution scratch the surface of the problem.</p>

<p>Find it difficult to be immune to··· 很难不受···的影响</p>

<p>e.g. with the development of globalisation and social development, one country finds it difficult to be immune to global affairs.</p>

<p>Be (severely/grievously) stricken with sth = be afflicted with/by = suffer from</p>

<p>受煎熬，遭难的，受折磨</p>

<p>e.g. The country ends up being stricken with the epidemic.</p>

<p>A bear/take the brunt of B A首当其冲受到B的不利影响</p>

<p>e.g. women bear the brunt of childcare duties</p>

<p>School will bear the brunt of cuts in govenment spending.</p>

<p>政府削减开支，学校将首当其冲受到影响</p>

<p>Fall prey to sth 受害，受坏影响</p>

<p>e.g. the new government has fallen prey to corruption and fraud.</p>

<p>新一届政府深受腐败和欺诈行为之苦</p>

<p>Be vulnerable to 容易受···(不好的)影响</p>

<p>e.g. The entity is potentially vulnerable to competitor’s moves.</p>

<p>Students are usually vulnerable to social evils. 易受到社会恶习腐蚀</p>

<p>Be prone to sth 易于遭受，有做(坏事)的倾向</p>

<p>e.g. tired, malnourished people are prone to infection.</p>

<p>Come with unpleasant/undesirable side-effects···伴随着不好的副作用</p>

<p>Fall victim to = become a victim of 成为···的牺牲品</p>

<p>e.g. Vital public services have fallen victim to budget cuts</p>

<p>一些重要的公众服务项目成了削减预算后的牺牲品</p>

<p>A take one’s toll on B A对B产生严重不良影响,造成重大损失</p>

<p>e.g. The recession is taking its toll on the housing markets. 经济衰退使住房市场遭受重创</p>

<p>The pressure of trying to win a competition has taken its toll on their health.</p>

<p>Illness had taken a heavy toll on her. 疾病对她的身体造成极大的损害</p>

<p>Shake/rock the foundations of sth 从根本上动摇···</p>

<p>e.g. this issue has shaken the foundations of French politics. 这个问题从根本上动摇了法国的政治</p>

<p>run counter to = be at odds with sth = conflict with 与···不相符/相矛盾</p>

<p>e.g. government intervening in people&rsquo;s private lives run counter to modern democratic spirit.</p>

<p>动词形式：interfere in/with = intervene in 干涉，介入</p>

<p>名词形式：interference in/with = intervention in/with</p>

<p>e.g. government should interfere in the coverage of media.</p>

<p>动词形式：impinge on/upon = encroach on/upon侵犯</p>

<p>名词形式：impringing on/upon = encroachment on/upon</p>

<p>e.g. one country should not impringe on other&rsquo;s internal affairs.</p>

<p>Be (potentially/rather/highly) hazardous to 对···有潜在/相当/很大的危害</p>

<p>e.g. chemicals that are harzardous to human beings</p>

<p>Defeat the very purpose of = render sth useless/ineffective 使某物无用/无效</p>

<p>e.g. Merely equipping students with employment skills may defeat the very purpose of universities as educational institutions.</p>

<p>Serve no useful purpose 不起作用</p>

<p>e.g. the experiments serve no useful purpose.</p>

<p>Be awash with sth = be inundated with sth 充斥着···</p>

<p>e.g. TV nowadays is awash with violent and pornographic content</p>

<p>Create a vicious circle 产生恶性循环</p>

<p>e.g. It turns out to be a vicious circle of destruction/ poverty</p>

<p>句子+ to the detriment of +名词 = Be detrimental to 有害于，不利于</p>

<p>e.g. He works longer and longer hours, to the detriment of his marriage.</p>

<p>Pose a grave threat to···对···构成威胁</p>

<p>e.g. In present-day society, the proliferation of non-biodegradable trash poses a grave threat to humanity.</p>

<p>句子+ at the expense of +名词 以（损害）···为代价</p>

<p>e.g. High production rates are often achieved at the expense of quality of work.</p>

<p>Be notorious for sth/ doing sth 因···而臭名昭著</p>

<p>e.g. The international fast foods have long been notorious as a kind of junk food.</p>

<p>Be apathetic to/about= be (utterly)indifferent to 对···冷漠/漠然</p>

<p>Not have sb’s best interests at heart 不关心···利益</p>

<p>e.g. People intend to maximize their own interest instead of having the best interests of the whole society at heart.</p>

<p>Get/grow weary of sth/ doing sth= lose interest in 对···不再热心</p>

<p>e.g. students grow weary of learning a series of historical fact.</p>

<p>Be reluctant to = be unwilling to 不愿意</p>

<p>e.g. People are reluctant to recycle garbage for the reason that they cannot acquire direct benefit from it.</p>

<p>Turn a blind eye to = shut one’s eyes to sth 对···视而不见</p>

<p>e.g. Those children have a good life and to turn a blind eye to patriotism</p>

<p>Have a slack attitude about对···持有疏忽的态度</p>

<p>Be largely ignored/neglected by···= lose sight of 被···忽略</p>

<p>e.g. Strange as it may seem, the significance of basic science – the main driving force behind productivity, has been largely ignored by the general public.</p>

<p>Addict oneself to doing = get/be(irreparably不可收复地/seriously) addicted to</p>

<p>= indulge oneself in = indulgence in 沉迷，放纵</p>

<p>e.g. addict oneself to gambling, drug, electronic game, pornograhy, delights of lesure (安逸)</p>

<p>Too much indulgence in the Internet games or movies may lead to a superficial (肤浅的) idiot (傻子) short of abstract thinking or may aggravate the isolation of the single children.</p>

<p>Give way to temptation= not resist the temptation to 经不住诱惑</p>

<p>e.g. the young are not mature enough so that they may not resist the temptation to conduct some unhealthy behaviours.</p>

<p>Be accused of = be prosecute for/as 被指责/被控告</p>

<p>= be on trial(审理) for</p>

<p>= Accuse/prosecute sb of doing/sth</p>

<p>= A stand accused of = stand trial/go on trial for A被控告···</p>

<p>lay/put the blame for sth on sb 把某事归咎某人</p>

<p>e.g. some lay the blame for falling exports on financial turmoil sweeping many Asian countries</p>

<p>有的人干脆认为造成出口下降的原因是横扫亚洲许多国家的金融危机。</p>

<p>be criticised for··· 因···受到批评</p>

<p>be condemned for/by··· 因···受到谴责 (宽恕 condone)</p>

<p>e.g. the action has been widely condemned by human rights groups</p>

<p>这一行动受到人权组织的普遍谴责</p>

<p>Deprive sb of sth 剥夺某人···</p>

<p>e.g. modern cities deprived city-dwellers of fresh air and the comfortable pace of life.</p>

<p>Be exposed to / expose sb to sth 使暴露于险境</p>

<p>e.g. The report revealed that workers had been exposed to unacceptably high levels of radiation 报告披露了工人们收到有害的高强度辐射</p>

<p>Sth prompts/ impels sb to do 促使···去做</p>

<p>e.g. Peer pressure often impels yongsters to spend excessively on fancy clothes and accessories (首饰)</p>

<p>If···, something will ensue 如果···，(不好的现象)接着发生</p>

<p>e.g. if parents neglect their offspring, lack of discipline and respect will ensue.</p>

<p>Sth is/seem (quite/totally/wholly) unwarranted/ unjustifiable很不合理</p>

<p>e.g. experimentaing upon lab animals without rying to alleviate their pain is unwarranted/ unjustifiable.</p>

<p>It is a waste of time/money/effort doing sth 浪费(时间/金钱)去做···</p>

<p>= squander = fritter away(time/energy/money/fortune)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Aim of a University Education ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/01/24/The-Aim-of-a-University-Education/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/01/24/The-Aim-of-a-University-Education</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<br />


<p>这篇文章典型的唠叨型……不过，刚好，观点很多。随便捡一两个来拓展就好了。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>&#8211;by John Henry Newman</p>

<p>节选之：</p>

<p>But a university training is the great ordinary means to a great but ordinary end; it aims at raising the intellectual tone of society, at cultivating the public mind, at purifying the national taste, at giving enlargement and sobriety to the idea of the age, at facilitating the exercise of political power, and refining the intercourse of private life.</p>

<p>It is the education which gives a man a clear, conscious views of his own opinions and judgments, a truth in developing them, an eloquence in expressing them, and a force in urging them. It teaches him to see things as they are, to go right to the point, to disentangle a skein of thought, to detect what is sophistical, and to discard what is irrelevant. It prepares him to fill any post with credit, and to master any subject with facility.</p>

<p>It shows him how to accommodate himself to others, how to throw himself into their stat of mind, how to bring before them his own, how to influence them, how to come to an understanding with them, and how to bear with them. He is at home in any society; he has common ground with every class; he knows when to speak and when to be silent; he is also to converse; he is able to listen; he can ask a question pertinently, and gain a lesson seasonably, where he has nothing to impart himself; he is ever ready, yet never in the way; he is a pleasant companion, and a comrade you can depend upon; he knows when to be serious and when to trifle, and he has a sure tact which enables him to trifle with gracefulness and to be serious with effect. He has the repose of a mind which lives in itself, while it lives in the world, and which serves him in public, and supports him in retirement, without which good fortune is but vulgar, and with which failure and disappointment have a charm.</p>

<p>The art which tends to make a man all this, is in the object which it pursues as useful as the art of wealth or the art of health, though it is less susceptible of method, and less tangible, less certain, less complete in its result.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Lessons preparing students for a st century workplace ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/01/24/Life-Lessons-preparing-students-for-a-st-century-workplace/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/01/24/Life-Lessons-preparing-students-for-a-st-century-workplace</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这篇文章关于为什么大学应该教授更多与工作相关的知识。阅读之后可以找到很多关于教育类考题大学教育的目的的词伙。</p>

<p>by Susannah Jackson</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Last week Education secretary Michael Gove asked some of the top universities in the UK to set A-level exams, amid fears that tens of thousands of teenagers<strong>are under-prepared</strong> when they start their degrees.</p>

<p>This means that 24 of the most academically competitive universities in the UK will be allowed to choose the content of the syllabus and questions on A-level exams.</p>

<p>But is this really what students need? It might be true that school exams don’t prepare people for university but similarly, university does not prepare its students for working life.</p>

<p>This year, the Office for National Statistics (ONS) revealed that the rate of unemployment among 21 year-old university graduates<strong>is roughly equal to</strong> that of 18 year-old school leavers, at 25 per cent and 26 per cent, respectively.</p>

<p>It is apparent that the university system is not doing enough to<strong>equip students with the skills they need to succeed</strong>. So, before the universities start to put their curriculum into schools they need to take a look at their own relevance to the workplace.</p>

<p>To do this they need to talk to businesses, find out the qualities that employers are looking for in their next star recruit and then work at fostering these attributes in their students.</p>

<p>Employers are looking for new starters to <strong>not just tick the boxes on a job description but to have the ambition to succeed in their own careers and the commercial outlook to grow businesses.</strong></p>

<p>These are <strong>qualities</strong> that need to be taught from school onwards, and to <strong>get the curriculum right</strong>, schools and universities<strong>need to be working with businesses at the very roots of the education system.</strong></p>

<p><strong>This approach has been embraced</strong> by our client Gazelle, a group of Further Education colleges that are bringing<strong>entrepreneurship</strong> into the heart of their operations. By working with some of the UK’s leading entrepreneurs, including Luke Johnson, Doug Richard, Lara Morgan and Will King, they are inviting business leaders in to advise on and inform the way they prepare students for the world of business.</p>

<p>There is an argument that this needs to<strong>happen across the entire education system</strong>.</p>

<p>The job-creators, the universities and government need to work together to provide the next generation with <strong>courses that will prepare and skill them</strong> for the 21st century<strong>workplace</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
