<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Downloads | LUKE'S IELTS ONLINE]]></title>
  <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/categories/downloads/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-12T17:49:19+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[somilk12]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pornography is everywhere and I think it;s changing how we feel about sex ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Pornography-is-everywhere-and-I-think-its-changing-how-we-feel-about-sex/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Pornography-is-everywhere-and-I-think-its-changing-how-we-feel-about-sex</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We arebattling a tsunami of smut that, far from being postmodern, clever or even sexy, is conceived to appeal to our basest instincts, stereotyping men as brainless Neanderthals and women as legitimate prey.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Thedilemma Why is it only children who we think might want to be protected from pornography? Do the rest of us have to live in this grossly objectifying and demeaning culture just because some people want access to porn? I find it interesting that objection tosexually explicit material finds a place as a parental issue – but it&rsquo;s much wider than that. I predict that there will be movements not only against pornography but actually against sex – that&rsquo;s the logical conclusion of all this, particularly with an ageing demographic. And I feel drawn that way. How important is sex? To whom? Why is it shaping our public and virtual spaces to such a degree?</p>

<p>Mariella replies It&rsquo;s a question I&rsquo;ve been asking myself, too. Just the other night as I drove into London I was confronted by a giant billboard selling me &ldquo;Pussy&rdquo;. There wasn&rsquo;t a feline in sight, just a photo of a new energy drink with the tagline: &ldquo;The drink&rsquo;s pure. It&rsquo;s your mind that&rsquo;s the problem.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I have to admit I&rsquo;m fast losing my sense of humour. It was unacceptable for the BBC to play the No 2 single &ldquo;Ding Dong the Witch is Dead&rdquo; in its entirety during the chart countdown despite it being a legitimate, if childish, way for those who didn&rsquo;t venerate Lady Thatcher to have their voices heard, yet it&rsquo;s OK to advertise a soft drink by naming it after slang for female genitalia? Where was the Advertising Standards Authority when that one was signed off?</p>

<p>We seem to have becomeimmune to the corrosive practice of using women&rsquo;s bodies to sell products and the widespread impact of the avalanche of pornography, spreading like a virus online. The links between demeaning representations of women and girls and the continuing (and in many areas escalating) violence against them is well documented, yet we continue totolerate the abuse of one sex for the supposed delectation of another. It&rsquo;s insulting to the intelligence of grown-ups and incredibly damaging to children. While schools are allowedto opt out of sex education, children increasingly get theirs online by watching the abuse (erroneously labelled pornography) which has replaced the misty-lensed erotica of days gone by.</p>

<p>Recently a friend told me that her 10-year-old son had been sent home from school for grabbing an older girl&rsquo;s breasts in the playground, squeezing them and going &ldquo;barp, barp&rdquo; to impress his little boy gang. When his mortified mother asked what had possessed him, he said he&rsquo;d watched a TV comedy where he&rsquo;d seen a guy do it and everyone laughed. And that&rsquo;s an innocent example. On my recent Radio 4 series Bringing Up Britain, Sue Berelowitz, the deputy children&rsquo;s commissioner, revealed that an entire class of Year 6 kids – 11-year-olds – who they&rsquo;d consulted for their report on the sexualisation of children had all watched pornography online.</p>

<p>Enjoying pornography may be a human right for consenting adults but perhaps we could adopt theGerman model, where those wanting to watch sex online have toopt in by signing up at their local post office. It would certainly sort the men from the boys, quite literally, which would be a step in the right direction. We are battling a tsunami of smut that, far from being postmodern, clever or even sexy, is conceived to appeal to our basest instincts, stereotyping men as brainless Neanderthals and women as legitimate prey. Men should be up in arms about the insult to their intelligence and to the women they love – mothers, sisters, wives and daughters – but the voice of opposition continues to be the preserve of the likes of Women&rsquo;s Hour and a few female commentators branded po-faced hysterics.</p>

<p>Ironically, with sex all around, it&rsquo;s interesting to learn from my postbag that many people feel like you: less and less inclined to actually have it. First our friendships were claimed by the virtual world; now our sex lives seem headed in the same direction. Were I to write a sci-fi novel I&rsquo;d set it in the near future, with humans becoming like the hideous breeder rats in James Herbert&rsquo;s novel Lair – deformed, amorphous lumps doing only what they are programmed for.</p>

<p>Once upon a time I thought the feminists of the 1970s were a pretty humourless lot, but increasingly I&rsquo;m missing their strident voices as we continue to tolerate thestatus quo – the sexual objectification of half of the population while brainwashing the other half to be so primitively programmed they fail to understand the boundaries of mutual respect. Surely it makes losers of both sexes?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Development must tackle jobs and migration say European thinktanks ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Development-must-tackle-jobs-and-migration-say-European-thinktanks/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Development-must-tackle-jobs-and-migration-say-European-thinktanks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Report says poverty should remain central, but calls for inclusive, sustainable model that emphasises jobs</p>

<p>Rocky road … A woman carrying mangoes walks past men doing laundry in Abidjan. Instability hashampered Ivory Coast&rsquo;s development.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>To eradicate poverty, the international community should pursue a wider and more far-reaching approach to development than was captured in the millennium development goals (MDGs), European thinktanks said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Although poverty should remain a core focus of the new agenda, the objective should be to tackle its causes by adoptinga more inclusive and sustainable development model that emphasises jobs and addresses inequality, according to the Overseas Development Institute (ODI), the European Centre for Development Policy Management and the German Development Institute.</p>

<p>Looking at thediffering experiences of Nepal, Rwanda, Ivory Coast and Peru, the European report on development stressed the importance of &ldquo;national ownership&rdquo;. The four were found to confirm the central importance of domestic political and economic policies as well as the external environment in creating opportunities or difficulties.</p>

<p>The report called on richer countries to collaborate in areas important to development such as international financial regulation, trade, migration and climate change. In a message to the EU in particular, the report called on member states to live up to the principle of policy coherence on development (PCD).</p>

<p>&ldquo;The concept of PCD is central, since it implies that all policies, and not merely development co-operation, should beconducive to development, eg policies in the areas of trade and investment or agriculture and fisheries should promote (or at the very least notthwart) development,&rdquo; said the report.</p>

<p>Claire Melamed from the ODI said some sort of global deal on trade and migration could be part of the agenda for what follows the MDGs when they expire in 2015.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Migration keeps coming up again and again among developing countries although it&rsquo;s one of thehardest political issues in the UK,&rdquo; she said at the OECD global forum on development in Paris last week. &ldquo;For developing countries it&rsquo;s a top priority and they want it to be tackled as part of a 2015 deal, so there has to be some nod to a conversation on migration … it is one of the biggest contributor to benefits to individuals and to countries.&rdquo;</p>

<p>PCD is highlycontentious, as developing countries have objected to what they see as unfair trade treaties being foisted upon them, agricultural subsidies in the US and the EU that underminefood security, and the unwillingness of rich countries to meet their aid commitments.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Official development assistance [ODA] targets will not be reached and PCD remains very difficult in practice,&rdquo; said the report. &ldquo;<strong>But perhaps the most crucial issue has been the failure of the international community to reach agreement on key issues such as climate change and trade or to achieve a stable and transparent international financial system.&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p>The OECD last week reported a drop in ODA for the second year running as countries cut foreign aid at a time of austerity. Aid fell by 4% in real terms last year to $125.7bn (£83bn), following a 2% dip in 2011.</p>

<p> <em>International co-operation, or global partnership</em>  for development, came under MDG eight, and was widely acknowledged as one of the least successful targets at last month&rsquo;s meeting in Bali of the UN high-level panel tasked with developing a post-2015 framework. The report said more extensive and reliable international action and support for development should be a core element of a new framework.</p>

<p> <em>Case studies</em>  <strong>confirmed</strong>  the fundamental importance of links with the global economy, financial flows, trade, migration and international co-operation – including south-south co-operation – in determining national development, said the report. Nepal, which integrated the MDGs into development plans, relied on remittances to support progress towards the targets. Rwanda, where the MDGs have played a central role, relies heavily on ODA, much of it in the form of budget support, which brings its own problems, and has made progress in mobilising domestic resources through taxation.</p>

<p>Ivory Coast has relied heavily on commodity exports, but progress towards the MDGs suffered as a result of instability. In Peru, the MDGs have been of limited relevance because of a pre-existing development consensus.</p>

<p>&ldquo;A new framework should pay more careful attention to how global goals relate to national policy needs and targets, respecting domestic policy space and linking national and international efforts in a mutually supportive and flexible manner,&rdquo; said the report.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pensioners hit by spiralling credit card debts forced to take out loans as energy prices soar ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/24/Pensioners-hit-by-spiralling-credit-card-debts-forced-to-take-out-loans-as-energy-prices-soar/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/24/Pensioners-hit-by-spiralling-credit-card-debts-forced-to-take-out-loans-as-energy-prices-soar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Pensioners hit by spiralling credit card debts forced to take out loans as energy prices soar</p>

<p>The Observer, Saturday 22 November 2008</p>

<!--more-->


<p>One in four people is approaching retirement with thousands of pounds worth of debt because they cannot meet the rising cost of living. Nearly half of over-55s are concerned about their depleted income, with one in eight now planning to continue working in order tobolster their income, a report claims.</p>

<p>&lsquo;With unemployment figures estimated to reach two million by December, it is possible that pensioners will find it harder than ever to find work,&rsquo; said Nigel Barlow of Just Retirement, the company behind the research. &lsquo;The likelihood is that poverty among pensioners is set to spiral out of control.&rsquo;</p>

<p> __ <br /></p>

<p> <em>Essential costs</em>  such as gas and electricity have surged by more than 40 per cent this year, meaning that disposable income isshrinking fast. Instead, over-55s are increasingly relying on credit cards, loans and overdrafts to pay their bills. The average credit card debt for the age group is now just over £8,000, according to separate figures from Key Retirement Solutions, a rise of £800 from last year.</p>

<p>A spokeswoman for debt charity the Consumer Credit Counselling Service (CCCS) said the research tallied with its own experience. &lsquo;Our clients are getting older and poorer,&rsquo; said Frances Walker. &lsquo;Last year for the first time more than half were over 40 compared with 44 per cent in 2005, while clients over 60 have the highest levels of debt, averaging nearly £30,000.&rsquo;</p>

<p>The rising figures highlight the consequence of a generation that became used to living off debt, credit cards and unsecured loans. Those who took out the first available credit card in 1967 had expected to pay off their debts by their forties and fifties but have instead found themselves hit by a double whammy of both their children and their parents being financially dependent on them for longer.</p>

<p>&lsquo;Add to these factors the rising cost of living and the credit crunch and you have a problem,&rsquo; said Walker. &lsquo;And we know that once you are retired it is very difficult to clear your debts.&rsquo;</p>

<p>Many retirees will struggle to manage on a rapidly shrinking pension that will have to cover rising living costs as well as pay off debts. The charity Age Concern said that even pensioners who retired owing nothing have since turned to credit cards or loans to pay their bills. &lsquo;On the whole older people havehistorically been more reluctant to get into debt. However, our recent research has shown that hikes in household bills have pushed one in 10 of the poorest pensioners into debt,&rsquo; said Gordon Lishman, director-general of Age Concern. &lsquo;There are also high levels of unsecured debt &#8211; such as credit card debt &#8211; among some people approaching retirement.&rsquo;</p>

<p>More than half of older people are nowcutting back on essentials such as heating and food, according to the charity, while more than a third of older people plan to live in one room of their home to save on fuel bills this winter, according to Help The Aged.</p>

<p>Despite increased living costs&#8230; up to £5bn in benefits is going unclaimed by some of the poorest pensioners because they don&rsquo;t know what they are entitled to &#8230; are worried about the complexity of the process or are embarrassed about claiming.</p>

<p>Sheila Hanham, 69, didn&rsquo;t know benefits were available before she spoke to Age Concern. &lsquo;I had been trying tomake do with very little for a long time and I was desperately worried about how I would get by as I got older. I just felt I couldn&rsquo;t survive,&rsquo; she said.</p>

<p>She now claims pension credit and other benefits and used £3,000 in backdated money owed to her to clear the debt on her credit card, which she had been using to pay bills.</p>

<p>Lishman said: &lsquo;In the currenteconomic turmoil it is important that adequate support and advice is given to the minority of older people who are in debt, and those who are at risk. Many older people will also be looking to the government to announce measures in itspre-budget report to help them with their finances.&rsquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
