<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: WRITING | LUKE'S IELTS ONLINE]]></title>
  <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/categories/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-12T22:12:43+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[somilk12]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sample essay for my own use ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/09/sample-essay-for-my-own-use/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/09/sample-essay-for-my-own-use</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> <em>A long-distance flight consumes the fuel as much as a car consumes in several years time, and causes the same amount of pollution as cars. So some people think we should abandon the non-essential fights (such as for tourism), and it is more efficient than restricting the car use. Give your opinion about it.</em></p>

<p>Tourism has fueled up air travel industry and its thriving creates millions of jobs and billions of revenue each year. Therefore, sorting tourism flights as non-essential is unreasonable and to ban these flights, although it would defuse the conflict between energy crisis and commercial profits temporarily, is to backfire both airtravel and tourism industry.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It is, indeed, reported that a long-distance flight consumes the amount of fuel that a car consumes in seven years. But it is also reported that major aerodynamic companies are investing both huge money and labor in the invention and improvement of energy-efficient engine and light materials to cut off fuel consumption and pollution. They are motivated to do so because fuel consumption accounts for up to 70% in their total running cost and the results are promising, light materials, more dual batteries and new engine have been invented and put into use, and they made a less 20%-40% fuel consumption possible.</p>

<p>In terms of air pollution, banning flights is not an effective way either. Traveling by flight has become an essential part for most modern people, including not only foreign trade businessmen, international journalists but also ordinary people who would travel or study abroad. the manmade prohibition will inconvenience these activities drastically and thus trigger public anger or even protests. It is democratic society, any decision made against the public’s interests would definitely araise mass dissensus, which would be a huge hurdle to the implementation.</p>

<p>Prohibiting is not the answer to everything that causes problems temporarily. To make a sensible policy is firstly to investigate the causes of the problems and then come up solutions accordingly. Any surfaced or immediate policy could, at best, scratch the surface of the problem and more often, creates more troubles than it solves. The banning of flight according to the so-called necessity would cause the latter, because it jump to the conclusion based on a single fact-huge consumption and pollution, but neglect the necessity of flights to the public and the inconvenience and anger that would come after such rude and much-too-simple solution. While others alternatives bring in good news, people, especially those policy makers, should at least give them a try. The banning, if needed, should be the last step to take, because it is just a passive way to solve any problem.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sample essay for my own use ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/sample-essay-for-my-own-use/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/sample-essay-for-my-own-use</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Some people think that traditional culture is being damaged as it is used as a tool to make money in the tourism industry. Others think it is the only way to preserve and protect culture and tradition. Discuss both views and give your own opinion.</strong></p>

<p>Official reports give information on the huge amount of revenue that tourism generated every year. However, the worry about the damage brought by this prospering industry is also mounting, the damage to local culture and tradition in particular. Whether tourism is the culprit behind the culture damage or the only protector for local culture and tradition has remained unsettled and it is time we have a close look on both arguments.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Tourism is a way but not the only way to protect culture and tradition. Today,  tourism industry ranks the fourth in the GDP contributing sector globally and it has created millions of jobs and more importantly brought in billions of revenue each year. This amount of money, as believed, can be used in the protection and maintainance of local historic relics and traditional culture because these cultural heritage is the biggest selling point in local tourism development. So it is the virtuous circle which generated money from and for local culture and tradition and a good way to protect and preserve indigenous culture.</p>

<p>On the other hand, it has been pointed out that tourism industry thrives at the price of local culture and environment. Being made as tourists attractions, local culture and tradition are becoming increasingly ‘artificial’ due to the overwhelming man inference in the process of creating a ‘tourist hot spot’ to attract visitors and money. A number of examples show that in order to attract tourists, many’hilarious and appealing to tourists’ traditional cultures have been rehearsed and put on shows in tourist destinations while other more reserved and difficult-in -understanding traditions are filtered and ignored. This manmade arrangement can be extremely hazardous to the protection of local tradition and culture because it changes the nature of them and more worse, it could make the local people regard the treat their convention and culture in a ‘money-oriented’ way.</p>

<p>Tourism, therefore, is a industry that brings in both good and harm. It is clear that this industry is not the only way to protect and preserve local culture and tradition despite the huge amount of revenue. It is a way to generate money to protect local cultural heritage and this is a worth-mentioned contribution. However, what it does to influence the way local people treat their culture should be supervised carefully, because if not, local culture and tradition would become a tool to earn money for the people instead of being an indispensable part in their lives as they used to be. So the two arguments are both melodramatic and a moderate and carefully-planned  development in tourism industry is now what people call for.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sustainability… A Growing Trend in Today’s Marketplace ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Sustainability-A-Growing-Trend-in-Todays-Marketplace/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Sustainability-A-Growing-Trend-in-Todays-Marketplace</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the continued demand for more energy efficient and environmentally friendly solutions, sustainability has become an important trend when choosing products for retail, healthcare, and other commercial applications.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>With the development of LED technology, advertising display productsare better able to meet these demands more than ever. When compared with other traditional light sources such as fluorescent and incandescent, LED consumes about 40% less power, making it extremely energy efficient.</p>

<p>In addition, it lasts anywhere from 50,000 to 100,000 hours – eliminating the need to replace lamps that can be harmful to the environment because of their mercury content. And, LED’s contain no mercury, making them an environmentally friendly choice.</p>

<p>All of these characteristics make LED technology a popular solution for sustainable projects. The really great thing about LED’s is that there is no sacrificing light quality for sustainability. This technology creates bright, white, uniform illumination making it the ideal choice to promote your product or service through eye-catching graphics. You can choose from a variety of sizes, shapes and profiles based on your specific needs.</p>

<p>Next time, use an LED light box to promote your business, and you’ll help improve your bottom line while also helping the planet!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Illegal logging robbing people in Africa of livelihoods – Global Witness ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Illegal-logging-robbing-people-in-Africa-of-livelihoods-%E2%80%93-Global-Witness/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/02/Illegal-logging-robbing-people-in-Africa-of-livelihoods-–-Global-Witness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Collusion between political elites, civil servants and logging companies issystematically robbing people of their livelihoods, says a report (pdf) into corrupt forestry practices in Africa.</p>

<p>The extensive granting of &ldquo;shadow permits&rdquo; for small-scale logging in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC), Liberia, Ghana and Cameroon bypasses new laws and environmental safeguards, and is forcing communities to meet their timber needs illegally, says NGO Global Witness.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The report, Logging in the shadows, identifies a &ldquo;hidden&rdquo; pattern of abuse in which hundreds of permits intended to promote small businesses and meet local needs are being allocated to large, often foreign, logging companies. These &ldquo;shadow permits&rdquo; open the door tolucrative, large-scale logging operations, which bypass the oversight of the authorities, it says.</p>

<p>In the DRC, dozens of artisanal logging permits were issued between 2010 and 2012, mostly to foreign industrial companies,violating DRC&rsquo;s forest laws in at least 10 different ways. In Liberia, companies have abused licences known as &ldquo;private use permits&rdquo; to buy a quarter of the country&rsquo;s totallandmass in only two years. In Ghana, the forestry commissionis said to have granted more than 400 logging permits secretly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;This is a veryworrying trend. Logging companies are systematically <strong>colluding with</strong> corrupt officialsto get around laws designed to stop themdecimating forests and abusing those who live in them. This is massivelyundermining international efforts to regulate thetimber trade,&rdquo; said Alexandra Pardal, Europe campaigner at Global Witness.</p>

<p>The report said: &ldquo;European-led reform efforts have focused on large-scale concessions that produce timber for export, but in each country shadow permits have provided aloophole to bypass tighter regulations. Weaknesses in legal frameworks and corruption at all levels of government have enabled companies to continue to export large amounts of timber to the EU, US and China.&rdquo;</p>

<p>According to Global Witness, €12.4bn (£10.5bn) worth of timber considered to pose a &ldquo;high risk&rdquo; of illegality entered the EU in 2011. On 3 March, a new EU law prohibited the import of illegal timber (pdf), but Global Witness and Greenpeace have uncovered suspicious log shipments at EU ports in the past two months.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Unless European and Africanpolicymakers <strong>take urgent action</strong> , shadow permits could become theTrojan horse by which illegal timber is brought into the EU and passed off as legitimate,&rdquo; said Pardal. &ldquo;Timber importers must do proper checks right the way along their supply chains to make sure they know exactly where their timber came from and whether the permit used to get it was legal.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saving Lives Livelihoods and Life ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/29/Saving-Lives-Livelihoods-and-Life/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-29T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/29/Saving-Lives-Livelihoods-and-Life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By Harold E. Varmus, Director of the U.S. National Cancer Institute; and Robert D. Hormats, Under Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment</p>

<p>For many people, the term biodiversity might seem highly technical and irrelevant to their day to day concerns. If you think that, think again. It may just save your life.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Biological diversity—or biodiversity—simplyrefers to the variety of plants, animals, and other living things on Earth.  <strong>The Earth’s biodiversity has an immense impact on our daily lives and cannot be taken for granted.</strong>  Today, Earth Day, is a chance to reflect on the value of our planet’s biodiversity and to take action to ensure that it is protected.</p>

<p>Tragically—and to the detriment of all of us— <strong>Earth’s biodiversity is disappearing at an alarming rate.</strong>  <strong>This is due to factors such as  </strong>deforestation, environmental degradation, and habitat destruction from agriculture, settlement, and other uses; pollution; climate change; and chronic over-exploitation or poaching of fish and wildlife species.<strong> </strong> Scientists estimate that the planet is losing species at a rate 1,000 to 10,000 times above the rate of species extinction that would occur normally without human activity. <strong>Particularly disheartening is the fact that</strong>, in many cases, we are losing species before we even know of them or know how they fit into our shared planet.</p>

<p><strong>The benefits of biodiversity are immeasurable</strong>. Biodiversity is the foundation of agriculture, forests, and fisheries.Plants and animals support tourism and trade. Biodiversity in ecosystems plays a critical role in the global carbon cycle and contributes to nutrient and water cycling. The loss of life on Earth—from microscopic bacteria to migratory birds—threatens the proper function of our planet. Moreover, biodiversity loss deprives humanity of scientific insights into the origins and evolution of life,as well as future beneficial discoveries in medicine, agriculture, and other fields.</p>

<p>There are numerous examples of advances stemming from bio-inspiration: The piranha bite-proof scales of the arapaima fish are being studied by scientists and engineers to develop new types of body armor that are strong yet flexible. Lessons learned from biological antifreeze proteins found in the blood of Arctic fish are being used to enhance cyro-preservation techniques for human organ transplants, improve the nutrition and taste of frozen foods, and increase the temperature tolerance of agricultural crops.</p>

<p><strong>Drawing inspiration from nature is not new.</strong> The Wright Brothers’ glider and airplane designs were based, in part, upon their observations of pigeons in flight. Wilbur Wright noticed that pigeons bent the tips of their wings to maintain proper balance and equilibrium in flight. This led to the breakthrough concept of wing-warping, which the Wright Brothers successfully used to control turning in their flier.</p>

<p><strong>Protecting our planet’s biodiversity is especially important to every one of us because it can help make the difference between life and death for ourselves and countless future generations.</strong> Medical history is ripe with examples of chemicals and pharmaceutical products derived from naturally occurring plants or bacteria that prevent or treat serious diseases. Among these are digitalis (found in foxglove and used to treat heart failure for at least three centuries); the many antibiotics found in soil bacteria; artemisinins (first used in China in the third century as an extract of sweet wormwood and now part of the standard treatment for malaria world-wide); taxol (from yew trees) and colchicine (from autumn crocus) used for treatment of many cancers and gout; and even aspirin (from willow bark) used to treat a wide variety of inflammatory disorders, allay pain, and prevent inappropriate clotting and certain cancers.</p>

<p><strong>Biodiversity loss runs the real risk of depriving us of the plants, animals, and microorganisms that could unlock cures for some of mankind’s most devastating ailments.</strong> Therefore—whether we suffer from a headache or heart disease—we all benefit from biodiversity and we all have a strong interest in fighting against the many policies and practices that threaten the variety of life on Earth.</p>

<p><strong>Once a species is gone, it is gone forever. Maintaining the Earth’s biodiversity—the broad and rich variety of life on our planet that is the product of billions of years of evolution—by preserving our forests, jungles, deserts, oceans, estuaries, and other habitats is critical to supporting the development of life-saving medicines and other bio-inspired innovations, as well as to ensuring the continued viability of our planet. Alternatively,</strong> the continued loss of biodiversity will seriously and adversely affect—in countless ways—all species, including Homo sapiens. If that fact fails to encourage all of us to make greater efforts to protect biodiversity, it is hard to know what will.</p>

<p>Harold Varmus, M.D., co-recipient of a Nobel Prize for studies of the genetic basis of cancer, is the Director of the National Cancer Institute. He previously served as President and Chief Executive Officer of Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center and as Director of the National Institutes of Health.</p>

<p>Robert Hormats, Ph.D., is the Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment at the U.S. Department of State. He previously served as Vice Chairman of Goldman Sachs (International), Assistant Secretary of State for Economic and Business Affairs, and Ambassador and Deputy U.S. Trade Representative.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
