<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Essay | LUKE'S IELTS ONLINE]]></title>
  <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/categories/essay/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-12T23:05:57+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[somilk12]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sample essay for my own use ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/09/sample-essay-for-my-own-use/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/09/sample-essay-for-my-own-use</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> <em>A long-distance flight consumes the fuel as much as a car consumes in several years time, and causes the same amount of pollution as cars. So some people think we should abandon the non-essential fights (such as for tourism), and it is more efficient than restricting the car use. Give your opinion about it.</em></p>

<p>Tourism has fueled up air travel industry and its thriving creates millions of jobs and billions of revenue each year. Therefore, sorting tourism flights as non-essential is unreasonable and to ban these flights, although it would defuse the conflict between energy crisis and commercial profits temporarily, is to backfire both airtravel and tourism industry.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It is, indeed, reported that a long-distance flight consumes the amount of fuel that a car consumes in seven years. But it is also reported that major aerodynamic companies are investing both huge money and labor in the invention and improvement of energy-efficient engine and light materials to cut off fuel consumption and pollution. They are motivated to do so because fuel consumption accounts for up to 70% in their total running cost and the results are promising, light materials, more dual batteries and new engine have been invented and put into use, and they made a less 20%-40% fuel consumption possible.</p>

<p>In terms of air pollution, banning flights is not an effective way either. Traveling by flight has become an essential part for most modern people, including not only foreign trade businessmen, international journalists but also ordinary people who would travel or study abroad. the manmade prohibition will inconvenience these activities drastically and thus trigger public anger or even protests. It is democratic society, any decision made against the public’s interests would definitely araise mass dissensus, which would be a huge hurdle to the implementation.</p>

<p>Prohibiting is not the answer to everything that causes problems temporarily. To make a sensible policy is firstly to investigate the causes of the problems and then come up solutions accordingly. Any surfaced or immediate policy could, at best, scratch the surface of the problem and more often, creates more troubles than it solves. The banning of flight according to the so-called necessity would cause the latter, because it jump to the conclusion based on a single fact-huge consumption and pollution, but neglect the necessity of flights to the public and the inconvenience and anger that would come after such rude and much-too-simple solution. While others alternatives bring in good news, people, especially those policy makers, should at least give them a try. The banning, if needed, should be the last step to take, because it is just a passive way to solve any problem.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sample essay for my own use ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/sample-essay-for-my-own-use/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/sample-essay-for-my-own-use</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Some people think that traditional culture is being damaged as it is used as a tool to make money in the tourism industry. Others think it is the only way to preserve and protect culture and tradition. Discuss both views and give your own opinion.</strong></p>

<p>Official reports give information on the huge amount of revenue that tourism generated every year. However, the worry about the damage brought by this prospering industry is also mounting, the damage to local culture and tradition in particular. Whether tourism is the culprit behind the culture damage or the only protector for local culture and tradition has remained unsettled and it is time we have a close look on both arguments.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Tourism is a way but not the only way to protect culture and tradition. Today,  tourism industry ranks the fourth in the GDP contributing sector globally and it has created millions of jobs and more importantly brought in billions of revenue each year. This amount of money, as believed, can be used in the protection and maintainance of local historic relics and traditional culture because these cultural heritage is the biggest selling point in local tourism development. So it is the virtuous circle which generated money from and for local culture and tradition and a good way to protect and preserve indigenous culture.</p>

<p>On the other hand, it has been pointed out that tourism industry thrives at the price of local culture and environment. Being made as tourists attractions, local culture and tradition are becoming increasingly ‘artificial’ due to the overwhelming man inference in the process of creating a ‘tourist hot spot’ to attract visitors and money. A number of examples show that in order to attract tourists, many’hilarious and appealing to tourists’ traditional cultures have been rehearsed and put on shows in tourist destinations while other more reserved and difficult-in -understanding traditions are filtered and ignored. This manmade arrangement can be extremely hazardous to the protection of local tradition and culture because it changes the nature of them and more worse, it could make the local people regard the treat their convention and culture in a ‘money-oriented’ way.</p>

<p>Tourism, therefore, is a industry that brings in both good and harm. It is clear that this industry is not the only way to protect and preserve local culture and tradition despite the huge amount of revenue. It is a way to generate money to protect local cultural heritage and this is a worth-mentioned contribution. However, what it does to influence the way local people treat their culture should be supervised carefully, because if not, local culture and tradition would become a tool to earn money for the people instead of being an indispensable part in their lives as they used to be. So the two arguments are both melodramatic and a moderate and carefully-planned  development in tourism industry is now what people call for.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sample essay of schooling and parenting(for my own use) ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/sample-essay-of-schooling-and-parenting-for-my-own-use/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/sample-essay-of-schooling-and-parenting-for-my-own-use</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> <em>c8t1</em></p>

<p>Children are the future. Therefore, early childhood education is the utmost priority on the importance list concerned by parents, schools and states. When it comes to who should be responsible for educating children into useful adults, there is an ongoing debate. Many advocate that comparing with school education, parenting is of more significance in this aspect.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Such beliefs are not groundless. Above all, parents are the first teacher to children. Their ways of thinking and behaviour decide what their children will be like in the future. As is reported, a child&rsquo;s basic skill of communication and language is formed in the first three years in his/ her life, and this indicates that any verbal and physical movement parents made in these three years will help to build a child&rsquo;s personality and a basic concept about people and the outside world. Moreover, the mindset of being grateful and respectful to good deeds and people are taught by parents. When parents take care of their older parents at home, their ways of helping the elderly have a great reflection on children' mind, which do lead a young to a lifelong way of showing respect to the old and the needed. Also, the ability of love and being loved is imparted by parents in a tender manner. A kid learn this ability by feeling the most earnest love to himself or herself from parents, and they start getting the importance of love and being loved. A person who can behave appropriately, respect and love others is believed to be a valuable member of society.</p>

<p>However, some still argue that rather than parenting, schooling in fact plays a more influential role in children' development. In their opinion, a child is supposed to obtain theoretical knowledge of a range of subjects and the ability to win the fierce competition among peers by attending normal schooling.Success it might lead children to, there is hardly any evidence linking schooling to the future of being a good community member in a child. No matter how successful a person could be, financially or academically, there is still a high possibility that a well-school-educated person finally turn out to be a selfish adult who has no basic passion towards human being and community. There are too many examples to illustrate  a higher education qualification dose not guarantee a well manner or behavior in that person. In comparison to parenting, which is widely thought as a necessary and sufficient condition in the process of educating children into valuable adults, schooling is believed only a necessary condition at its best.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sample essay for youth unemployment(for my own use) ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/09/sample-essay-for-youth-unemployment-for-my-own-use/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/09/sample-essay-for-youth-unemployment-for-my-own-use</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> <em>rubric: what are the causes and solutions of youth unemployment?</em></p>

<p>Youth unemployment is a chronic issue. This social problem is not a single-cause case but a result from many social forces, especially in economy, culture and the disproportion in higher education arrangement of curriculum. This essay will analyze the major causes behind this trend and highlight some responsible solutions.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Many fresh graduates take graduation as the time being unemployed, while the increasing rate of youth unemployment reconfirms this fear. With the recent break out of economic recession, first in the USA, then in Japan and Europe, this trend has been exacerbated. Under such circumstance, many companies started to cut off its man power as well as limit the number of newly recruited employees. This makes it hard for an experienced worker to keep his or her job, let alone new graduates finding a position in such an economic hardship. Also, it is long been discussed that higher education fails to meet the need of providing the society and labor market with students who master no only theoretical knowledge but practical skills. As a result, the average performance of young graduates at work is relatively unsatisfying, which leads to an avoidance of recruiting first-year graduates in many companies. And this is another factor which intensifies the situation of youth unemployment.</p>

<p>According to those causes analyzed above, several measures should be put into effect in the near future. First of all, an economic recovery is the surefire cure for this situation, which asks for the very effort from governments. Governors can draw a strategy after through study of the job market stimulation policy enacted by Roosevelt-introducing big infrastructure programs to underdeveloped area&#8211;to consume a big number of labors. Secondly, the insufficiency of higher education should be filled as soon as possible, including opening courses about the office manner and dress code in certain company culture, to compensate the scarcity of work experience in students. Again, more connections should be bridged between students and companies. Take Holland for example, it mandates students to accomplish the target of taking internship during college period. This method allows students to have a better acquaintance with the way how a company is operated and how to get along with colleagues in office.</p>

<p>In conclusion, youth unemployment is a social issue which is resulted from many social changes. If the solutions identified above are implemented, the situation of this issue will be largely improved.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sample essay for environmental protection(for my own use) ]]></title>
    <link href="http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/08/Sample-essay-for-environmental-protection-for-my-own-use/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lukeielt.github.io/blog/2013/04/08/Sample-essay-for-environmental-protection-for-my-own-use</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> <em>Rubric:</em></p>

<p> <em>Some people think that pollution and damage of environment are resulting from a country&rsquo;s developing and becoming richer, and this is hard to be avoided. To what extent do you agree or disagree?</em></p>

<!--more-->


<p>With the economic boom,the pollution and environmental degradation are becoming increasingly serious. Some people argue that this is the inevitable outcome of a country’s economic development. Personally, I am of this opinion.</p>

<p>The industrial development has thus far consumed a variety of non-renewable resources and produced pollution. Due to industrialization, non-renewable resources, including fossil fuel and other raw materials are consumed at an alarming rate. It is universally acknowledged that these resources are limited and once being depleted, they would not be restored within a short time. More worse is that the consumption of natural resources produces pollutions and it is proved that the consumption of fossil fuel is the main reason behind the ever-severe air pollution.</p>

<p>And until now, human race still is far away from the balance between development and ecosystem sustainability. The anti-pollution measures are futile in front of the irreversible eager of developing economy; the government compromises to the commercial benefits brought by highly-polluted industries, including energy industry and chemistry industry; people hold the view that “environmental conservation is second to economic development”. This shows that economic development has driven people ahead, leaving environmental protection behind.</p>

<p>However, it should be noted that some countries have succeeded in both economic and environmental development. For example, Swiss and some north European countries, such as Norway, have set good examples for other nations about how to develop economy and protect the environment at the same time. But compared with the typical modes of development in most countries, these examples are just some exceptions.</p>

<p>In conclusion, I believe that the economic development is thriving at the price of environment and this is an inevitable trend. However, people should never give up the effort of maintaining environment while developing economy for this effort will certainly pay back when the country is financially and technologically capable of tackling environmental problems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
